<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Francesco Regazzoni | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/francesco-regazzoni/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/author/francesco-regazzoni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Francesco Regazzoni</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Francesco Regazzoni</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/francesco-regazzoni/</link></image><item><title>Cryptographic Engineering</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/cryptographic_engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/cryptographic_engineering/</guid><description/></item><item><title>This week at CCI: CARDIS 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/cardis-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/cardis-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>The 22nd Smart Card Research and Advanced Application Conference (CARDIS 2023),
hosted by CCI in LAB42, is taking place this week, with tutorials on Tuesday
and research talks on Wednesday and Thursday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CARDIS has been the venue for security experts from industry and academia to
exchange on security of smart cards and related applications since 1994. Smart
cards play an increasingly important role in our day-to-day life through their
use in banking cards, SIM cards, electronic passports, and IoT devices. It is
thus naturally of utmost importance to understand their security features and
to develop sound protocols and countermeasures while keeping reasonable
performance. In this respect, CARDIS aims to gather security experts from
industry, academia, and standardization bodies to make steps forward in the
field of embedded security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Find the full program on the official website
&lt;a href="https://sbd-research.nl/cardis-2023/program.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted at DATE 2024</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/date-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/date-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our paper, &lt;strong>Demonstrating Post-Quantum Remote Attestation for RISC-V Devices&lt;/strong>,
authored by Maximilian Barger (MSc Computer Security student at VU Amsterdam),
Marco Brohet and Francesco Regazzoni, has been accepted as an extended abstract
at the &lt;a href="https://www.date-conference.com/date-2024-accepted-papers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2024 Design, Automation &amp;amp; Test in Europe Conference &amp;amp; Exhibition (DATE)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The rapid proliferation of Internet of Things (IoT)
devices has revolutionized many aspects of modern computing.
Experience has shown that these devices often have severe security
problems and are common targets for malware. One approach to
ensure that only trusted software is executed on these devices is
Remote Attestation, which allows a verifier to attest the integrity
of software running on such a prover device. As malware is
typically not trusted, an infected device will fail to generate a
valid signature, which allows the verifier to detect the presence
of malware on the prover. To achieve its security guarantees,
Remote Attestation requires a trust anchor, often found in the
form of dedicated hardware on the prover. For IoT and embedded
devices such hardware has only recently become largely deployed.
Modern Remote Attestation protocols rely on classical asymmetric
signatures that are vulnerable to quantum attacks, which are
expected to become feasible in the near future. Considering the
extensive usage of IoT and embedded systems combined with
their long lifetime (in some applications), it is necessary to be
able to retrofit these devices to support quantum secure Remote
Attestation without incurring a prohibitive overhead. In this paper
we present SPRAV, a software-based Remote Attestation system
that leverages the Physical Memory Protection (PMP) primitive of
RISC-V to achieve its security guarantees and employs quantum-
safe cryptographic algorithms to ensure resistance against quan-
tum attacks in the future. Our evaluation shows that it is feasible
to deploy this solution on RISC-V devices without incurring a
prohibitive overhead or the need for additional hardware, paving
the way towards quantum-resistant functionalities also in IoT.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction to Security</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/introduction_to_security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/introduction_to_security/</guid><description>&lt;p>Security is one of the most important extra-functional property of systems. Essential yet often overlooked, security ensures that our daily transactions remain protected, that our infrastructure operates regularly and that our communication stays private and safe from unauthorized parties. The aim of Introduction to Security is to provide solid foundations on the overall security domain, starting from the core components of cryptographic theory, implementations and cryptanalysis. Subsequently, it shows how secure are used to build the cryptographic protocols deployed in our everyday life, and we continue by covering the fundamentals of operating systems&amp;rsquo; security, intrusion detection/prevention and recent research topics such as privacy-preserving technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within CCI, our research strives to develop and apply open-source, efficient, protected and tailor-made cryptographic implementations that ensure the security, privacy and availability of our society&amp;rsquo;s communication infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Best Short Paper Award at CompSys 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/compsys-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/compsys-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LargeResearch/status/1674378448763072513" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Photo&lt;/a>
courtesy of the @Large Research group at the VU.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maximilian Barger, &lt;a href="https://vu.nl/en/education/master/computer-security" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MSc Computer Security&lt;/a>
student at the Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, conducted a research project
under the supervision of CCI members Marco Brohet and Francesco Regazzoni on
implementing post-quantum remote attestation on RISC-V devices. He presented his
work at CompSys 2023 and received the Best Short Paper Award. Congratulations, Max!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.compsys.science/conference/current/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">International Conference on Computer Systems (CompSys)&lt;/a>
is the premier forum for Dutch research into Computer Systems research. The aim
is to showcase success stories while also fostering and strengthening collaboration.
CompSys 2023 was hosted at &lt;a href="https://www.kontaktderkontinenten.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hotel Kontakt der Kontinenten&lt;/a>
in Soesterberg.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Presented at IJCNN 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ijcnn-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ijcnn-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Tom (left) and Danny at their research poster. Photo courtesy of Danny.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Danny van den Berg, &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/programmas/bachelors/beta-gamma/beta-gamma.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BSc Natural and Social Sciences&lt;/a>
student majoring in Artificial Intelligence, wrote his thesis under the supervision
of Tom Slooff (&lt;a href="https://usi.to/bbhb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USI&lt;/a>) and CCI. The resulting paper,
&lt;em>&amp;lsquo;Data Under Siege: The Quest for the Optimal Convolutional Autoencoder in
Side-Channel Attacks&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em>, co-authored with Tom Slooff, Marco Brohet, Kostas
Papagiannopoulos, and Francesco Regazzoni, was accepted to be presented at
IJCNN 2023. Congratulations, Danny!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://2023.ijcnn.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/a>
is the premier international conference in the area of neural networks theory,
analysis and applications. IJCNN 2023 was hosted at the &lt;a href="https://www.gccec.com.au/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gold Coast Convention and Exhibition Centre&lt;/a>
in Queensland, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Encryption is a method to keep our data safe from third parties. However,
side-channel information may be leaked during encryption due to physical
properties. This information can be used in side-channel attacks to recover
critical values such as the secret encryption key. To this end, it is necessary
to understand the robustness of implementations to assess the security of data
handled by a device. Side-channel attacks are one such method which allow
researchers to evaluate the robustness of implementations using appropriate
metrics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the security community, machine learning is playing a
prominent role in the study of side-channel attacks. A notable
example of this is the use of Convolutional Autoencoders (CAE)
as a preprocessing step on the measurements. In this work
we study in depth the problem of finding the most suitable
architecture of such Convolutional Autoencoders. To this end,
Optuna is used to explore the CAE hyperparameter space. This
process allows us to identify hyperparameters that outperform
state-of-the-art autoencoders, reducing the needed traces for
a succesful attack by approximately 37% in the presence of
Gaussian noise and reducing the trainable parameters needed
to attack desynchronization by a factor of 29. In addition to the
promising results, experiments carried out in this paper allow
a better understanding of the hyperparameter space in the field
of side channel attacks, providing a solid base for future use of
CAE in this specific domain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Published at ACM Computing Surveys</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-published-csur/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-published-csur/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper &amp;lsquo;A Survey on Thwarting Memory Corruption in RISC-V&amp;rsquo;, authored by
Marco Brohet and Francesco Regazzoni, has been published at ACM Computing Surveys.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The paper is published as open-access and can be found in ACM&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3604906" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Library&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With embedded devices becoming more pervasive and entrenched in society, it is
paramount to keep these systems secure. A threat plaguing these systems consists
of software vulnerabilities that cause memory corruption, potentially allowing
an attacker to breach the device. Software-based countermeasures exist, but
suffer from high overhead. In this survey, we investigate whether this could be
mitigated using dedicated hardware. Driven by the advancements of open hardware,
we focus on implementations for RISC-V, a novel and open architecture tailored
for customization. We distinguish between methods validating memory accesses
beforehand, obfuscating information necessary for an attack, and detecting
memory values corrupted earlier. We compare on qualitative metrics, such as the
security coverage and level of transparency, and performance in both software
and hardware. Although current implementations do not easily allow for a fair
comparison as their evaluation methodologies vary widely, we show that current
implementations are suitable to minimize the runtime overhead with a relatively
small area overhead. Nevertheless, we identified that further research is still
required to mitigate more fine-grained attacks such as intra-object overflows,
to integrate into more sophisticated protected execution environments towards,
resilient systems that are automatically recoverable, and to move towards more
harmonized evaluation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Call for Papers: CARDIS 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/cardis-2023-cfp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/cardis-2023-cfp/</guid><description>&lt;p>CARDIS has been the venue for security experts from industry and academia to
exchange on security of smart cards and related applications since 1994. Smart
cards play an increasingly important role in our day-to-day life through their
use in banking cards, SIM cards, electronic passports, and IoT devices. It is
thus naturally of utmost importance to understand their security features and
to develop sound protocols and countermeasures while keeping reasonable
performance. In this respect, CARDIS aims to gather security experts from
industry, academia, and standardization bodies to make steps forward in the
field of embedded security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 22nd edition of CARDIS will be organized by Francesco Regazzoni, Kostas
Papagiannopoulos and Marco Brohet from the Complex Cyber Infrastructure group
of the University of Amsterdam in Amsterdam, NL. CARDIS 2023 will be an
in-person event, with the possibility to attend talks remotely (presenters are
required to participate to the conference in presence).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Find out more on the official website
&lt;a href="https://sbd-research.nl/cardis-2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two PhD positions on efficient privacy-preserving techniques for data analysis and machine learning</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>How can the privacy of health-related personal data be preserved, while using data analysis and machine learning for innovative medical approaches?
What privacy-preserving techniques should be used and how, to achieve given privacy and utility objectives?
How to implement privacy-preserving techniques to achieve efficiency and scalability?
Work on the answer to these questions as PhD candidate in our research group! See the details and apply here as soon as possible:
&lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Two-PhD-Positions-on-Efficient-Privacy-preserving-Techniques-for-Data-Analysis-and-Machine/760571802/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Two-PhD-Positions-on-Efficient-Privacy-preserving-Techniques-for-Data-Analysis-and-Machine/760571802/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Post-Quantum Cryptography: Challenges and Opportunities for Robust and Secure HW Design</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/bellizia-post-quantum-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/bellizia-post-quantum-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>An Instruction Set Extension to Support Software-Based Masking</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/gao-instruction-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/gao-instruction-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Guest Editors’ Introduction: Special Issue on Top Picks in Hardware and Embedded Security</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/cammarota-guest-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/cammarota-guest-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Security, Reliability and Test Aspects of the RISC-V Ecosystem</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/abella-security-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/abella-security-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Special Section on Attacking and Protecting Artificial Intelligence</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/bhasin-special-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/bhasin-special-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Deeper Look at the Energy Consumption of Lightweight Block Ciphers</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/caforio-deeper-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/caforio-deeper-2021/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>