<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/</link></image><item><title>Project Software Engineering</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/project_software_engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/project_software_engineering/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Operating Systems</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/operating_systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/operating_systems/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the Operating Systems course, students learn how applications
interact with the hardware via the operating system, and how the
operating system solves various tasks for the applications such as CPU
scheduling, and memory and storage management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Understanding these basics is very important to analyse and tune the
performance of a system to a particular application. In the Complex
Cyber Infrastructure group, we are often dealing with very high
performance hardware, such as 400 Gbps fiber links, and large storage
volumes. To have e.g. data-processing applications make full use of this
hardware, requires tuning the operating system to the specific workload,
and this is where the fundamental operating system knowledge comes in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Classical Cryptography</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/classical_cryptography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/classical_cryptography/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Compiler construction</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/compiler_construction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/compiler_construction/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cryptographic Engineering</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/cryptographic_engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/cryptographic_engineering/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Data Protection Technologies</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/data_protection_technologies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/data_protection_technologies/</guid><description>&lt;p>The course focuses on technologies that can be used to protect data from unauthorized access. The main motivation is to protect personal data and comply with data protection legislation such as the General Data Protection Regulation of the European Union. The course&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>explains the context of data protection technologies from multiple angles (e.g., legal requirements, interplay with other quality attributes);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>conveys in-depth knowledge on some specific data protection technologies (e.g., cryptographic protocols for secure multi-party computation, anonymization and pseudonymization, differential privacy, access control, anonymous communications);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>showcases applications of data protection technologies (in particular, privacy-preserving machine learning and location privacy).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The course is closely linked to the research performed by CCI researchers in the field of security and privacy (for example, in the &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/project/secured/">SECURED&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/project/fogprotect">FogProtect&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi">EPI&lt;/a> projects).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Organisatie: analyse en ontwikkeling</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/organisatie_analyse_en_ontwikkeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/organisatie_analyse_en_ontwikkeling/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Programmeertalen</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/programmeertalen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/programmeertalen/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Web and Media Tech</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/web_and_media_tech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/web_and_media_tech/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Computer Systems</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/computer_systems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/computer_systems/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introduction to Security</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/introduction_to_security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/introduction_to_security/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Netwerkorganisatie</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/netwerkorganisatie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/netwerkorganisatie/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Lorentz workshop on Future Computing for Digital Infrastructures</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/lorentz-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/lorentz-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.lorentzcenter.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lorentz Center&lt;/a> hosted a week-long international workshop on &lt;a href="https://www.lorentzcenter.nl/future-computing-for-digital-infrastructures.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Future Computing for Digital Infrastructures&lt;/a>. More than 40 experts participated and discussed current and future challenges and potential solutions in computing, including the effects on computing by artificial intelligence, sustainability, and security. CCI was represented by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/viktoriya-degeler/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Viktoriya Degeler&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan Mann&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @IEEE TPS 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-tps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-tps/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>Enabling Collaborative Multi-Domain Applications: A Blockchain-Based Solution with Petri Net Workflow Modeling and Incentivization&lt;/b> by Zhou, X., Cushing, R., Koning, R., Belloum, A., Grosso, P., Klous, S., van Engers, T. &amp; de Laat, C. was accepted at &lt;a
http://www.sis.pitt.edu/lersais/conference/tps/2023/">The Fifth IEEE International Conference on Trust, Privacy and Security in Intelligent Systems, and Applications&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The increasing value of data and the emergence of programmable infrastructures have paved the way for collaborative multi-domain applications across industries such as healthcare and airlines. However, such collaborations come with significant challenges, including application coordination, incentivization, and validation of execution. In this paper, we propose a novel solution that leverages blockchain technology and utilizes Petri nets for workflow modeling. Our approach involves implementing a smart contract-based workflow coordinator on the blockchain and employing a three-layered architecture to coordinate off-chain tasks. Additionally, we demonstrate the use of Petri nets for modeling economy tokens, which serve as incentives to foster collaboration among workflow parties. To validate our solution, we present a proof of concept through a simulated use case involving a multi-domain workflow for mitigating a DDoS attack. In this use case, domains collaborate by blocking offending IPs, incentivized by acquired tokens required to invoke workflows.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Published@AMC 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-published-amc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-published-amc/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>The dynamics of corruption under an optional external supervision service&lt;/b> by Xin Zhou, Adam Belloum, Michael H. Lees, Tom van Engers, Cees de Laat has been published at &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0096300323003417">Applied Mathematics and Computation&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>External supervision services play an important role in combating corruption by detecting potential collusive bribery. This work aims at studying the dynamics of collusive bribery when participants have the option of engaging the external supervision services. To do so, we construct a basic model where collusive bribery can happen between the defecting participants who aim to escape from a punishment by offering a bribe to rule enforcers who monitor interactions among all participants. Among rule enforcers, only the corrupt ones accept the bribe and ignore the violations. The cooperative participants can engage the external supervision service at a certain cost to avoid the risk of potential collusive bribery. Under the framework of evolutionary game theory, we find that a higher initial fraction of honest enforcers is more likely to lead to a trusting cooperating equilibrium. We also find that, when allowing random exploration of available strategies, increasing the exploration rate of rule enforcers is effective in combating corruption for both infinite and finite populations. Lastly, we find that minimizing the cost of external supervision services is not always good. When the system evolves into a cooperating equilibrium, a low cost of external supervision service induces unnecessary costs of seeking external supervision. When the strategy profiles exhibit stable oscillations, there exists an optimal cost of external supervision, considering the trade-off between minimizing the chance of exposing cooperative participants to collusive bribery and strengthening the punishment on the corrupt enforcers. Premised on the results, we discuss practical management suggestions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Best Short Paper Award at CompSys 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/compsys-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/compsys-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LargeResearch/status/1674378448763072513" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Photo&lt;/a>
courtesy of the @Large Research group at the VU.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maximilian Barger, &lt;a href="https://vu.nl/en/education/master/computer-security" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MSc Computer Security&lt;/a>
student at the Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, conducted a research project
under the supervision of CCI members Marco Brohet and Francesco Regazzoni on
implementing post-quantum remote attestation on RISC-V devices. He presented his
work at CompSys 2023 and received the Best Short Paper Award. Congratulations, Max!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.compsys.science/conference/current/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">International Conference on Computer Systems (CompSys)&lt;/a>
is the premier forum for Dutch research into Computer Systems research. The aim
is to showcase success stories while also fostering and strengthening collaboration.
CompSys 2023 was hosted at &lt;a href="https://www.kontaktderkontinenten.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hotel Kontakt der Kontinenten&lt;/a>
in Soesterberg.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Presented at IJCNN 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ijcnn-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ijcnn-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Tom (left) and Danny at their research poster. Photo courtesy of Danny.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Danny van den Berg, &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/programmas/bachelors/beta-gamma/beta-gamma.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BSc Natural and Social Sciences&lt;/a>
student majoring in Artificial Intelligence, wrote his thesis under the supervision
of Tom Slooff (&lt;a href="https://usi.to/bbhb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USI&lt;/a>) and CCI. The resulting paper,
&lt;em>&amp;lsquo;Data Under Siege: The Quest for the Optimal Convolutional Autoencoder in
Side-Channel Attacks&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em>, co-authored with Tom Slooff, Marco Brohet, Kostas
Papagiannopoulos, and Francesco Regazzoni, was accepted to be presented at
IJCNN 2023. Congratulations, Danny!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://2023.ijcnn.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)&lt;/a>
is the premier international conference in the area of neural networks theory,
analysis and applications. IJCNN 2023 was hosted at the &lt;a href="https://www.gccec.com.au/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gold Coast Convention and Exhibition Centre&lt;/a>
in Queensland, Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Encryption is a method to keep our data safe from third parties. However,
side-channel information may be leaked during encryption due to physical
properties. This information can be used in side-channel attacks to recover
critical values such as the secret encryption key. To this end, it is necessary
to understand the robustness of implementations to assess the security of data
handled by a device. Side-channel attacks are one such method which allow
researchers to evaluate the robustness of implementations using appropriate
metrics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the security community, machine learning is playing a
prominent role in the study of side-channel attacks. A notable
example of this is the use of Convolutional Autoencoders (CAE)
as a preprocessing step on the measurements. In this work
we study in depth the problem of finding the most suitable
architecture of such Convolutional Autoencoders. To this end,
Optuna is used to explore the CAE hyperparameter space. This
process allows us to identify hyperparameters that outperform
state-of-the-art autoencoders, reducing the needed traces for
a succesful attack by approximately 37% in the presence of
Gaussian noise and reducing the trainable parameters needed
to attack desynchronization by a factor of 29. In addition to the
promising results, experiments carried out in this paper allow
a better understanding of the hyperparameter space in the field
of side channel attacks, providing a solid base for future use of
CAE in this specific domain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Published at ACM Computing Surveys</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-published-csur/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-published-csur/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper &amp;lsquo;A Survey on Thwarting Memory Corruption in RISC-V&amp;rsquo;, authored by
Marco Brohet and Francesco Regazzoni, has been published at ACM Computing Surveys.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The paper is published as open-access and can be found in ACM&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3604906" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Digital Library&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With embedded devices becoming more pervasive and entrenched in society, it is
paramount to keep these systems secure. A threat plaguing these systems consists
of software vulnerabilities that cause memory corruption, potentially allowing
an attacker to breach the device. Software-based countermeasures exist, but
suffer from high overhead. In this survey, we investigate whether this could be
mitigated using dedicated hardware. Driven by the advancements of open hardware,
we focus on implementations for RISC-V, a novel and open architecture tailored
for customization. We distinguish between methods validating memory accesses
beforehand, obfuscating information necessary for an attack, and detecting
memory values corrupted earlier. We compare on qualitative metrics, such as the
security coverage and level of transparency, and performance in both software
and hardware. Although current implementations do not easily allow for a fair
comparison as their evaluation methodologies vary widely, we show that current
implementations are suitable to minimize the runtime overhead with a relatively
small area overhead. Nevertheless, we identified that further research is still
required to mitigate more fine-grained attacks such as intra-object overflows,
to integrate into more sophisticated protected execution environments towards,
resilient systems that are automatically recoverable, and to move towards more
harmonized evaluation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Just happened: Programming Languages in the Netherlands (PLNL) 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/plnl-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/plnl-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>The workshop Programming Languages in the Netherlands, supported by &lt;a href="https://versen.nl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">VERSEN&lt;/a>, was a big success. A 12-presentation programme enticed plenty of discussion amoung the 50-60 participants. The CCI group contributed by organising the event (Thomas and Grace) and by giving two talks (Christopher on Seaso and Damian on language services).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many thanks to Grace for the help in organising the event, resulting in a very smooth workshop experience. The attached pictures give an impression of the event hosted in the Doelenzaal of the university library.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PLNL is still looking for organisers for next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="crowd.jpg" alt="PLNL2023">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inter-faculty UvA funding success for CCI projects</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/rdt-projects-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/rdt-projects-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please find &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/en/content/news/news/2023/05/theme-based-collaboration-enters-next-phase-with-awarding-of-midsize-projects-and-seed-grants.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this&lt;/a> announcement on the internal (UvA) funding awarded for interdisciplinary research within certain themes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thomas, Ana, and Tom with &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/en/about-the-uva/about-the-university/strategy/theme-based-collaboration/responsible-digital-transformations.html#Data-sharing-through-a-data-intermediary" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;Data sharing through a data intermediary&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ana with the project &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/en/about-the-uva/about-the-university/strategy/theme-based-collaboration/responsible-digital-transformations.html#Sustainable-privacyenhanced-data" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;Sustainable privacy-enhanced data&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Postdoc Position on Digitally Enforceable Data Sharing contracts</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/sspddp-postdoc-spring2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/sspddp-postdoc-spring2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>The University of Amsterdam (UvA) is looking for a Postdoctoral Researcher in the area of programming languages, formal methods, and distributed systems. The goal of the research is to enable the integration and automatic enforcement of high-level contract specification within distributed systems for data exchange and federated data processing. Possible outcomes are: (domain-specific) software languages, system architecture designs, and prototypes for verifying contract specifications, language implementations, and auditing/monitoring components. The offered contract is for a minimum of 12 months. The closing date is the 25th of June. The ideal starting date the 1st of August.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The full vacancy text and application procedure can be found here: &lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Postdoc-Position-on-Digitally-Enforceable-Data-Sharing-Contracts/771937302/">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Postdoc-Position-on-Digitally-Enforceable-Data-Sharing-Contracts/771937302/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Call for Papers: CARDIS 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/cardis-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/cardis-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>CARDIS has been the venue for security experts from industry and academia to
exchange on security of smart cards and related applications since 1994. Smart
cards play an increasingly important role in our day-to-day life through their
use in banking cards, SIM cards, electronic passports, and IoT devices. It is
thus naturally of utmost importance to understand their security features and
to develop sound protocols and countermeasures while keeping reasonable
performance. In this respect, CARDIS aims to gather security experts from
industry, academia, and standardization bodies to make steps forward in the
field of embedded security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 22nd edition of CARDIS will be organized by Francesco Regazzoni, Kostas
Papagiannopoulos and Marco Brohet from the Complex Cyber Infrastructure group
of the University of Amsterdam in Amsterdam, NL. CARDIS 2023 will be an
in-person event, with the possibility to attend talks remotely (presenters are
required to participate to the conference in presence).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Find out more on the official website
&lt;a href="https://sbd-research.nl/cardis-2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SNE Volleybal Team Outshines Competition</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/fnwi-volleybal-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/fnwi-volleybal-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Participating at the Faculty of Science&amp;rsquo;s annual volleybal tournament, Team
&lt;em>Snelle Jelle and the Daltons&lt;/em> featuring among others CCI members Tim, Damian,
Christopher and Marco, won the &lt;strong>Most Cheerful Outfit&lt;/strong> prize.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Out of the 16 teams participating, the &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5659248/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>The Daltons&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
look-alikes with fellow members of the MNS and PCS research groups from our SNE
cluster, managed to conquer the 11th place. A very nice result for the first
particpation, which we could not have achieved without our dedicated SNE
supporters that kept cheering for us until the very end. A special thanks to you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Read more about it in the Faculty&amp;rsquo;s staff website
&lt;a href="https://medewerker.uva.nl/en/science/content-secured/news/2023/05/faculty-volleyball-tournament-photanol-sils-wins-again.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Invited talk at the 2023 Privacy Symposium</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/privacy-symposium-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/privacy-symposium-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> gave an invited talk at this year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://privacysymposium.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Privacy Symposium&lt;/a>, in the session &lt;em>From Cloud to Edge Security&lt;/em>. Entitled &lt;strong>Edge intelligence: friend or foe? (for security and privacy)&lt;/strong>, Zoltan&amp;rsquo;s presentation discussed the security and privacy implications of artificial intelligence in edge computing. It drew attention to the recent BDVA position paper &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/post/bdva-pospaper-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Current Hot Topics in Data Protection&lt;/a> as well CCI&amp;rsquo;s recently started EU research project &lt;a href="https://secured-project.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SECURED&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Downloaded Article in Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/wiley-top-downloaded-article-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/wiley-top-downloaded-article-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wiley awarded a &amp;ldquo;Top Downloaded Article&amp;rdquo; certificate to &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> for his paper &lt;a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1002/cpe.6138" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Comparison of workload consolidation algorithms for cloud data centers&lt;/a>, published in the journal &lt;em>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience&lt;/em>. This certifies that the paper was one of the most downloaded during its first 12 months after publication, among work published in 2021. The paper was joint work with Rene Ponto (University of Duisburg-Essen, Germany) and Gabor Kecskemeti (Liverpool John Moores University, UK).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IFIP WG11.4 elects Zoltan Mann as new chair</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ifip-11-4-chair/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ifip-11-4-chair/</guid><description>&lt;p>IFIP Working Group 11.4 &amp;ldquo;Network &amp;amp; Distributed Systems Security&amp;rdquo; elected &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> as the new chair of the working group in its meeting on 16 March 2023. Zoltan takes over the chair role from &lt;a href="https://www.uni-regensburg.de/informatik-data-science/wi-kesdogan/team/prof-dr-dogan-kesdogan/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Professor Dogan Kesdogan&lt;/a>, who will continue as secretary of the working group. The new chair and secretary work as acting officers until they are approved by the &lt;a href="https://www.ifiptc11.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IFIP Technical Committee 11&lt;/a> in June 2023.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://ifip.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IFIP&lt;/a>, the International Federation for Information Processing, is the leading multinational, apolitical organization in Information &amp;amp; Communications Technologies and Sciences. It connects researchers worldwide in over 100 Working Groups and 13 Technical Committees.
IFIP Technical Committee 11 is concerned with security and privacy protection in information processing systems, and consists of 14 working groups, addressing different aspects of security and privacy. Working Group 11.4 focuses on security in networks and distributed systems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @IEEE eScience 2022</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-escience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-escience/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>Exploring the Enforcement of Private, Dynamic Policies on Medical Workflow Execution&lt;/b> by Christopher A.
Esterhuyse, Tim Muller, Thomas van Binsbergen, and Adam S. Z. Belloum was accepted at &lt;a
href="https://www.escience-conference.org/2022/">18th IEEE eScience Conference 2022: Democratizing Science&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We report on the ideas and experiences of adapting Brane, a workflow execution framework, for use cases involving medical
data exchange and processing. These use cases impose new requirements on the system to enforce policies encoding safety
properties, ranging from access control to legal regulations pertaining to data privacy. Our approach emphasizes users' control
over the extent to which they cooperate in distributed execution, at the cost of revealing information about their policies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @PPAI23</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-ppai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-ppai/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>On Achieving Privacy-Preserving State-of-the-Art Edge Intelligence&lt;/b> by Daphnee Chabal, Dolly Sapra,
and Zoltan Mann was accepted at &lt;a
href="https://aaai-ppai23.github.io">&lt;b>4th AAAI Workshop on Privacy-Preserving Artificial Intelligence&lt;/b>&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Deep Neural Networks (DNNs) Inference in Edge Computing, often coined Edge Intelligence, requires solutions to insure that
sensitive data confidentiality and intellectual property are not revealed in the process. Privacy-preserving Edge Intelligence
is only emerging, despite the growing prevalence of Edge Computing as a context of Machine-Learning-as-a-Service. Solutions have
yet to be applied to state-of-the-art DNNs. This position paper provides an original assessment of the compatibility of existing
techniques for privacy-preserving DNN Inference with the characteristics of an Edge Computing setup. The resulting favorite
candidate is secret sharing. We then address the future role of model compression methods in the research towards secret sharing
on DNNs with state-of-the-art performance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Assistant or Associate Professor in Security and Privacy</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2023-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2023-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>Join our team!
We have an open position in the broad area of security and privacy.
The position can be filled on the level of either Assistant Professor or Associate Professor.
See the details and apply here by 15 February 2023:
&lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Assistant-or-Associate-Professor-in-Security-and-Privacy/761330802/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Assistant-or-Associate-Professor-in-Security-and-Privacy/761330802/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SECURED</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/project/secured/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/project/secured/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Two PhD positions on efficient privacy-preserving techniques for data analysis and machine learning</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>How can the privacy of health-related personal data be preserved, while using data analysis and machine learning for innovative medical approaches?
What privacy-preserving techniques should be used and how, to achieve given privacy and utility objectives?
How to implement privacy-preserving techniques to achieve efficiency and scalability?
Work on the answer to these questions as PhD candidate in our research group! See the details and apply here as soon as possible:
&lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Two-PhD-Positions-on-Efficient-Privacy-preserving-Techniques-for-Data-Analysis-and-Machine/760571802/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Two-PhD-Positions-on-Efficient-Privacy-preserving-Techniques-for-Data-Analysis-and-Machine/760571802/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Symposium in honor of Cees de Laat and Leon Gommans</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/symposium-cees-leon-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/symposium-cees-leon-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>A symposium entitled &lt;strong>‘From Systems and Networks to Complex Cyber Infrastructures’&lt;/strong> took place on 9th December 2022 in honor of Cees de Laat and Leon Gommans.
On the one hand, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cees de Laat&lt;/a>, the former Chair of CCI, retired recently.
This symposium looked at where the systems, networking and complex cyber infrastructures field stands today, a field to which Cees has contributed greatly.
On the other hand, the symposium celebrated &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/leon-gommans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leon Gommans&lt;/a> for becoming Professor by Special Appointment in the area of Complex Cyber Infrastructure for Data Exchange Systems within CCI.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="an-afternoon-with-a-lot-of-insights-personal-memories-and-fun">An afternoon with a lot of insights, personal memories, and fun&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Turing Zaal in Amsterdam Science Park was packed with people, some of whom came from other continents to salute Cees and Leon on this special occasion.
The audience enjoyed talks by a lineup of distinguished speakers.
The symposium was opened by &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/profiel/g/r/p.grosso/p.grosso.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paola Grosso&lt;/a> from the Multiscale Networked Systems group.
In the first talk, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/leon-gommans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leon Gommans&lt;/a> explained how multi-domain authorization research evolved into data exchange systems research.
Leon was followed by &lt;a href="https://crd.lbl.gov/divisions/amcr/about-amcr/staff/computer-science/john-shalf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John Shalf&lt;/a>, Department Head for Computer Science at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, who talked about the future of computing beyond exascale.
The first session ended with a very personal talk by &lt;a href="https://www.vuhpdc.net/henri-bal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Henri Bal&lt;/a> from Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, entitled &amp;ldquo;Networking with Cees&amp;rdquo;.
After the break, Dutch Internet pioneer &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kees_Neggers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kees Neggers&lt;/a> took the floor with a historical overview from ARPANET to complex cyber infrastructures.
In the sequel, the second speaker from the USA, &lt;a href="https://www.sdsc.edu/research/researcher_spotlight/wuerthwein_frank.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Frank Würthwein&lt;/a>, Director of the San Diego Supercomputer Center, focused on the future of open research platforms.
The last talk was given by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cees de Laat&lt;/a>, who shared several insights as well as numerous funny and memorable moments from his career.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The symposium, which was organized by the &lt;a href="https://mns-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Multiscale Networked Systems&lt;/a> group, the &lt;a href="https://pcs-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Parallel Computing Systems&lt;/a> group, and CCI, ended with a reception, giving the attendants the opportunity to meet old and new friends.
For sure, this afternoon will be a pleasant and inspiring memory for the people who had the honor to be present.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @AICOL-JURIX 2022</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-aicol/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-aicol/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>Regulatory Services to Automate Compliance with Ex-post Enforcement&lt;/b> by Lu-Chi Liu, Mostafa Mohajeri Parizi, Thomas van Binsbergen, and Tom van Engers was accepted at &lt;a href="http://www.aicol.eu/">AICOL 2022: AI Approaches to the Complexity of Legal Systems&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Software systems are expected to comply with norms from a variety of sources. However, the increasing volume and the dynamism of norms make it rather difficult to have a fully compliant software system by design. This paper proposes a generic architecture of regulated software systems that facilitates compliance with high-level policies through regulatory services. Our architectural model has the flexibility to adapt to norm modifications and to norm violations by including ex-post enforcement mechanisms. The proposed solution is assessed using a case study and a prototype implementation in the eFLINT and ASC2 languages for modeling norms and software/social agents respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @JURIX2022</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-jurix/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-jurix/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>Can a military autonomous device follow International Humanitarian Law?&lt;/b> by Tomasz Zurek, Jonathan Kwik, Mostafa Mohajeriparizi and Tom Van Engers was accepted at &lt;a href="https://jurix2022.rechtsinformatik.saarland/">&lt;b>35th International Conference on Legal Knowledge and Information Systems&lt;/b>&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The paper presents a formal model and an experimental verification of the system controlling the International Humanitarian Law compliance for the autonomous military device.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BDVA position paper on data protection</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/bdva-pospaper-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/bdva-pospaper-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Big Data Value Association (BDVA) has just published a new position paper on the latest trends in data protection.
Entitled &amp;ldquo;Current Hot Topics in Data Protection&amp;rdquo; and edited by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan Mann&lt;/a>, the position paper summarizes the latest challenges as well as promising technologies in data protection.
It also presents recommendations for authorities, industry, researchers, and other stakeholders.
You can find more information and download the paper &lt;a href="https://bdva.eu/bdva-publishes-position-paper-latest-trends-data-protection" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Another Paper Accepted @SLE22</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/second-paper-accepted-at-sle22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/second-paper-accepted-at-sle22/</guid><description>&lt;p>The CCI group is well presented at the &lt;a href="https://2022.splashcon.org/home/sle-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15th edition of the Software Language Engineering (SLE)&lt;/a> with
another paper being accepted, titled: &lt;strong>A Language-Parametric Approach to Exploratory Programming Environments&lt;/strong>
by Thomas van Binsbergen, Damian Frolich, Mauricio Verano Merino, Joey Lai, Pierre Jeanjean, Tijs van der Storm, Benoit Combemale, and Olivier Barais.
This paper is a collaboration with the &lt;a href="https://www.diverse-team.fr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DiverSE team from Inria&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://www.cwi.nl/research/groups/software-analysis-and-transformation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CWI SWAT group&lt;/a>, and a significant contribution from a &lt;a href="https://scripties.uba.uva.nl/search?id=record_30195" target="_blank" rel="noopener">master&amp;rsquo;s thesis&lt;/a> done at the CCI group.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Exploratory programming is a software development style in which code is a medium for prototyping ideas and solutions, and in which even the end-goal can evolve over time. Exploratory programming is valuable in various contexts such as programming education, data science, and end-user programming. However, there is a lack of appropriate tooling and language design principles to support exploratory programming. This paper presents a host language- and object language-independent protocol for exploratory programming akin to the Language Server Protocol. The protocol serves as a basis to develop novel (or extend existing) programming environments for exploratory programming such as computational notebooks and command-line REPLs. An architecture is presented on top of which prototype environments can be developed with relative ease, because existing (language) components can be reused. Our prototypes demonstrate that the proposed protocol is sufficiently expressive to support exploratory programming scenarios as encountered in literature within the software engineering, human-computer interaction and data science domains.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @SLE22</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-at-sle22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-at-sle22/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;strong>iCoLa: A Compositional Meta-language with Support for Incremental Language Development&lt;/strong>
by Damian Frolich and Thomas van Binsbergen is accepted at the &lt;a href="https://2022.splashcon.org/home/sle-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15th edition of the Software Language Engineering (SLE)&lt;/a> conference.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Programming languages providing high-level abstractions can increase programming productivity and safety. Language-oriented programming is a paradigm in which specialized languages are developed to solve problems within specific domains with (high-level) abstractions relevant to those domains. However, language development involves complex design and engineering processes. These processes can be simplified by reusing (parts of) existing languages and by offering language-parametric tooling. In this paper we present iCoLa, a meta-language supporting incremental (meta-)programming based on reusable components. In our implementation of iCoLa, languages are first-class citizens, providing the full power of the host-language (Haskell) to compose and manipulate languages. Finally, we demonstrate iCoLa through a case-study in which we construct &lt;em>Imp&lt;/em>, &lt;em>SIMPLE&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>MiniJava&lt;/em> through the composition and restriction of language fragments and demonstrate the variability of our approach through the construction of several languages using a fixed-set of operators.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open PhD position</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-09/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-09/</guid><description>&lt;p>Is it possible to reduce the energy consumption of machine learning, while increasing its security and privacy? Work on the answer as PhD candidate in our research group! See the details and apply here by 20 September 2022:
&lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/PhD-Position-in-Energy-and-Security-of-Machine-Learning-Applications-in-the-Cloud-to-Edge-Continuum/745019702/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/PhD-Position-in-Energy-and-Security-of-Machine-Learning-Applications-in-the-Cloud-to-Edge-Continuum/745019702/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Markermeer: the CCI social event</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/social-event-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/social-event-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>To end the academic year in style, the &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Complex Cyber Infrastructure&lt;/a> group went on a sailing trip on the Markermeer.
Before the sailing trip could take off, the group needed to gather in the harbour of Monnickendam &amp;mdash; a beautiful old city with plenty of sightseeing and picture opportunities.
&lt;img src="8P9A9066.JPG" alt="Early birds">&lt;/p>
&lt;p align = "center">
Waiting in the harbour for all members to arrive
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After everyone arrived in the harbour, the captain gave a bit of history on the boat.
The boat was several centuries old, had different owners over time and experienced a couple of world events.
One such event is the second world-war. Since the boat can reach shallow water, it was of upmost interest to the
Germans, because it could be used to supply soldiers on beaches. To prevent usage by the Germans, the boat was
hidden in the Biesbosch during the war.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With some new knowledge on our hands, the sailing trip started. Before sailing with the sails, the boat
went out of the harbour using an engine. This gave todays pirates time to fill their bellies before their labour was needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p float="center" style="display: inline-block;">
&lt;img src="8P9A9073.JPG" width="48%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;img src="8P9A9079.JPG" width="48%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arrived on open water, we could set sail. However, first the sails needed to be hoist.
Several strong members of the group volunteered for this activity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p float="center">
&lt;img src="8P9A9101.JPG" width="48%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;img src="8P9A9128.JPG" width="48%" style="display: inline;" />
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the sails hoisted and a good wind, it was time to relax, socialise and enjoy a couple of drinks.
&lt;img src="8P9A9299.JPG" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p float="center">
&lt;img src="8P9A9223.JPG" width="49%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;img src="8P9A9333.JPG" width="49%" style="display: inline;" />
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a beautiful couple of hours on the water while catching some good winds, it was time
to return to the harbour for a nice barbeque and to welcome &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/ana-oprescu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ana&lt;/a> and her entourage on to the boat.
But first, there were two brave souls, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thomas&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/daphnee-chabal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Daphne&lt;/a>, taking the opportunity to swim.&lt;/p>
&lt;p float="center">
&lt;img src="8P9A9372.JPG" width="49%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;img src="8P9A9363.JPG" width="49%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="8P9A9424.JPG" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, it was a great day and being on a sailing boat was a new experience for some. Interesting conversations and discussions were held and new friendships were made.
Are you interested in joining our social event next year? Keep an eye on our news sections for open positions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="acknowledgements">Acknowledgements&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Thanks to &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/yuri-demchenko/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yuri&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/arno-bakker/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Arno&lt;/a>
for taking pictures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @EUMAS2022</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-eumas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-eumas/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>Introducing Normative Advisors into MAS&lt;/b> by Mostafa Mohajeri Parizi, Thomas van Binsbergen, Giovanni Sileno and Tom van Engers was accepted at &lt;a href="http://www.ccc.cs.uni-duesseldorf.de/eumas2022/">The 19th European Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This paper introduces a modular architecture for integrating norms in autonomous agents and multi-agent systems. As the the interactions between norms and agents can be complex, this architecture utilizes multiple programmable components to model concepts such as adoption of multiple personal and/or collective possibly conflicting norms, interpretation and qualification between social and normative contexts, possibility of intentionally (non-)compliant behaviors and resolving conflicts between norms and desires (or other norms). The architecture revolves around &lt;i>normative advisors&lt;/i> that act as the bridge between intentional agents and the institutional reality. As a technical contribution, a running implementation of the architecture is presented based on the ASC2 (AgentScript) BDI framework and eFLINT norm reasoner.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Master Software Engineering student papers accepted at BENEVOL’22</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/papers-accepted-at-benevol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/papers-accepted-at-benevol/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bas van den Brink’s work on applying model-based testing to microservices has been accepted as a proceedings contribution to &lt;a href=
"https://benevol2022.github.io/">BENEVOL’22&lt;/a>. He is supervised by Ana Oprescu, Tannaz Zameni (University of Twente), Lammert Vinke (Info Support), and Dr. Ulyana Tikhonova (Axini). This project is of particular interest to the &lt;a href="https://www.versen.nl/contents/works/masters-thesis-projects">VERSEN Master’s Thesis Projects Working Group&lt;/a> as an example of multi-university multi-industry collaboration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anjali Ahlawat’s work on a practical maintainability model for data models has also been accepted as a presentation abstract. She is supervised by Ana Oprescu, and two SIG supervisors, Xander Schrijen, and Bugra M. Yildiz.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ana Oprescu on Travelling as a Mom</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-traveling-as-a-mom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-traveling-as-a-mom/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wrote this short piece about travelling with my baby. My point with this, is to bring attention to a compromise parents might not have to make anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Work traveling with Maria.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my home country, mothers can spend up to two years of almost fully paid maternal leave. The Netherlands, with their 16 weeks is a far cry. Luckily, my husband, a freelancing mathematician, can travel with me and take care of Maria while I am participating in the various work activities. As such, Maria has already joined the Nijmegen SusTrainable Teacher Training before she had turned 1, and then joined ICT4S and the SusTrainable summer school. It has not been easy, and the EU does not help in any way, but the UvA is a great employer in this sense, and I can focus much better while traveling for work, knowing I will join Maria in the late afternoon, as if a normal day at ‘home’.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ana Oprescu will join as co-chair the Amsterdam Data Science Thesis Award PC</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/anna-join-ds-award/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/anna-join-ds-award/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please send your Bachelor and/or Master thesis nominations &lt;a href="https://amsterdamdatascience.nl/news/2022-ads-thesis-awards/#:~:text=Amsterdam%20Data%20Science%20(ADS)%20is,the%208th%20of%20December%202022">here&lt;/a>. There is a special second track supporting diversity. Contact Ana at a.m.oprescu[at]uva.nl for any questions or clarifications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Presentation by Ana Oprescu @ICT4S</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-presented-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-presented-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ana Oprescu presented her &lt;a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9830083/">paper&lt;/a> on the Energy Cost and Accuracy of K-anonymity in &lt;a href="https://conf.researchr.org/series/ict4s">ICT4S&lt;/a> (Mon 13 - Fri 17 June 2022 Plovdiv, Bulgaria).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
​​European Union has aggregated the current societal concerns into two seemingly orthogonal directions: the Green Deal and the GDPR. In this paper, we begin to analyse trade-offs in preserving privacy, learning from the data, and saving energy. Considerable research studied the energy efficiency of software and the accuracy of machine learning models trained on anonymised datasets. However, to the best of our knowledge, no research has been conducted on the impact of anonymisation techniques on energy consumption. We measure the impact of anonymisation on the energy consumption and on the accuracy of machine learning models.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
We find that the k-value has a statistically significant impact on the energy consumption of the chosen anonymization algorithms. In terms of the accuracy of machine learning models, the generalisation and suppression performs better in almost all cases, provided that proper anonymization hierarchies are used in the anonymization process. However, we find that for the larger and more complex dataset, the reduction in accuracy is limited while there is a significant difference in energy consumption. Thus when considering energy consumption we conclude that for larger datasets it might be worthwhile to consider using microaggregation over generalisation and suppression.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the same event, Lukas Koedijk also presented the &lt;a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9830107/">paper&lt;/a> co-authored with Ana Oprescu based on his master graduation project on the Energy Footprint of Programming Languages. Lukas is an alumnus of the Software Engineering master, now working at KPMG.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The EU Green Deal mirrors the societal concern regarding climate change. In the software industry this means reducing the energy consumption of a program. This can be done by looking both at the hardware and the software used. We take a software approach and focus on the programming language choices and how a computer program is written. The programming languages we investigate are Java, JavaScript, Python, PHP, Ruby, C, C++ and C#. We compare programs from The Computer Language Benchmarks Game and these programs are divided in groups that solve the same problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We find that the choice of programming language and the way of writing your program influences the energy consumption. The programming languages that consume the least amount of energy over all the problems are C and C++, albeit these programming languages consume more energy when compilation flags are minimized. However, in some cases we could not prove that there was a difference in the energy consumption. We also find that the hardware used to run the programs has an influence on the energy consumption. We find that the runtime of a program correlates with the energy consumption, but a shorter runtime does not necessarily result in a lower energy consumption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the colocated &lt;a href="https://gsd.web.elte.hu/events/sustrainable">SusTrainable workshop&lt;/a>, Ana also presented current research efforts on Energy-driven Software Engineering. The workshop was organised by the Erasmus+ project &lt;a href="https://sustrainable.github.io/">SusTrainable&lt;/a>, in which UvA is a partner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The EU Climate Law targets climate neutrality by 2050. At the same time, the Knowledge Economy is deemed crucial to EU prosperity. Thus, the energy footprint of software services remains an important topic of research and education. In these lecture notes, we set out to educate students on energy-aware software engineering. We show how to establish whether some programming languages are inherently more “green”. We also show how to assess whether established software smells (anti-patterns) are also energy-related smells.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Software Engineering master student Nuria Bruch wins VERSEN Master Thesis Award!</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/nuria-versen-award/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/nuria-versen-award/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nuria Bruch, supervised by Ana Oprescu, Miroslav Zivkovic and Lodewijk Bergmans wins the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sig_eu/status/1525150139614171138">VERSEN Master Thesis Award&lt;/a> for her work on &lt;a href="https://zenodo.org/record/4280883#.YtqQxdJByV5">measuring the degree of library dependency!&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The usage of libraries, both commercial and open-source, encapsulating the implementation of certain functionalities is a widespread practice among developers. However, when a developer uses a library in a software product, this creates a dependency, and if a library has a security issue, it can be propagated to the software product. Developers can use package managers, however, these generally offer a simple binary evaluation of the dependencies: either there is one or not. Hence, a detailed evaluation of the dependencies is missing, which could help developers deal with vulnerabilities, breaking changes, and deprecated dependencies. Nuria proposes a model for software dependencies, which can help provide a fine-grained evaluation of them. The model includes three types of metrics: coupling, coverage, and usage per class. For each metric in the model, Nuria provides a formal definition and a theoretical validation by proving the metrics’ properties. She additionally implemented a proof-of-concept tool that, given a library from the Maven Central Repository, calculates the metrics of the model for each of the dependencies using bytecode analysis. Moreover, the proof-of-concept includes a visualisation of the dependency tree, including the calculated metrics. Finally, she conducted experiments to validate the model, the implementation of the proof-of-concept, and the visualisation. The experiments include interviews with 15 professional developers who evaluated the clarity and actionability of the model’s metrics and the proposed visualisations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SusTrainable summer school</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-presented-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-presented-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>During the &lt;a href="https://sustrainable.uniri.hr/">Rijeka SusTrainable summer school&lt;/a> (4-8 July 2022, Rijeka, Croatia) organised by the Erasmus+ project SusTrainable Ana Oprescu gave a lecture on the methodologies employed for Energy-driven Software Engineering research. This was followed by a hands-on session prepared together with Kyrian Maat and based on work by Lukas Koedijk, Stephan Kok and Sander van Oostveen. The school was well attended by UvA master and PhD students, as well as junior lecturers.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visit of Inder Monga</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/visit-indermonga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/visit-indermonga/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week we had a visit from Inder Monga, director ESnet, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. In this visit we had many discussions on the already 2 decades of working together on different advanced networking topics. In particular we are starting up cooperation on Quantum Networking and we are a partner in the experimental networks testbed &lt;a href="https://www.whatisfabric.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FABRIC&lt;/a>, where &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">prof. de Laat&lt;/a> serves on the Scientific Advisory Board. FABRIC (FABRIC is Adaptive ProgrammaBle Research Infrastructure for Computer Science and Science Applications) is an International infrastructure that enables cutting-edge experimentation and research at-scale in the areas of networking, cybersecurity, distributed computing, storage, virtual reality, 5G, machine learning, and science applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later this year (components shortage permitting) we will receive a FABRIC node in Amsterdam for our students and researchers to experiment on with our programmable networks and data exchange research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Friday July 8th Inder presented a colloquium with the title:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ESnet: Advancing networking for Science and the science of Networking&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Abstract&lt;/em>: Research and Education networks play a key role in providing the
data infrastructure to accelerate scientific discovery. This talk will discuss
how the leading Department of Energy user facility in the United States,
ESnet, contributes to scientific discovery and the set of network research
activities including quantum networking currently in progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Biographical Sketch&lt;/em>: Inder Monga provides research and technology
direction, actively leads research projects and manages software engineering
efforts for ESnet. He focuses on advancing networking services for
accelerating collaborative and distributed science, as well as contributes
actively to efforts in the industry related to Software-Defined Networking,
Science DMZ, performance management as well as the Advanced Network
Testbed Initiatives. He is appointed as the chair of ONF&amp;rsquo;s Research
Associates, and contributes actively to the Global Network Architecture
activity. Monga’s research interests include network virtualization, software-
defined networking, grid/cloud computing and sensor networking, and he
holds 17 granted patents. His work experience in the private sector has
included software development, research and network engineering for
Wellfleet Communications and Nortel, where he focused on application and
network convergence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Costly incentives design from an institutional perspective: cooperation, sustainability and affluence</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/proceeding_a_xin_2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/proceeding_a_xin_2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>SLICES-PP Receives Funding from the European Commission</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/slices-pp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/slices-pp/</guid><description>&lt;p>Scientific Large Scale Infrastructure for Computing/Communication
Experimental Studies -preparation project (SLICES-PP) is a project with
25 partners and a budget of 3 M€ for 4 years. The UvA will receive 303
K€ and it will be led by Yuri Demchenko of the Informatics Institute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Demchenko, from the CCI (Complex Cyber Infrastructure) group, will
coordinate two topics in SLICES-PP, first Research Data Management in
the SLICES infrastructure, and secondly SLICES capacity building and
career management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a part of activities in SLICES-PP, UvA will also facilitate creating
a SLICES-NL community and involving Dutch research organizations and
universities. The goal is to define the research agenda for SLICES-NL
and coordinate efforts to obtain national funding. In this connection,
new SLICES-NL coordination meetings will be organised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SLICES as a European Research Infrastructure aims to make a fundamental
contribution to research and innovation in digital sciences and
infrastructures, future Internet technologies, future smart networks and
services by providing high quality experimentation services with
emerging technologies around the area of digital sciences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new research infrastructure will allow academics and industry to
experiment and test future, possibly disruptive digital technologies,
essential for European research. This infrastructure can be beneficial
for other scientific and engineering domains, such as smart cities,
energy, green technologies and healthcare.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SLICES-PP will coordinate the preparatory stage to build the future
SLICES Research Infrastructure for Digital Technologies experimentation.
The project was submitted by consortium of 25 research institutions and
centers from 15 countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SLICES-RI (Research Infrastructure) is included in the ESFRI Roadmap
2021 as a new RI for digital technologies experimentation, together with
other already existing RI and e-Infrastructures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://slices-ri.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">More Information&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper accepted at SEAA 2022</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accept-seaa2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accept-seaa2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper &amp;ldquo;UMLsec4Edge: Extending UMLsec to model data-protection-compliant edge computing systems&amp;rdquo; has been accepted as a full paper at the 48th Euromicro Conference on Software Engineering and Advanced Applications (SEAA 2022).
The paper, authored by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> with co-authors from the University of Duisburg-Essen, presents a new UML profile for improved modeling of data protection aspects in edge computing systems.
The practical applicability of the new UML profile is demonstrated with the use cases of the EU-funded research project FogProtect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change of Group Leadership</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</guid><description>&lt;p>As of 1 June 2022, leadership of the Complex Cyber Infrastructure research group was transferred from Prof. Cees de Laat to Dr. Zoltan Mann.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof.dr.ir. Cees de Laat&lt;/a> chaired the System and Network Engineering (SNE) research group since 2006. SNE became so large that on his proposal it was split into three successful research groups in 2020: Complex Cyber Infrastructure (CCI), the Multiscale Networked Systems (MNS), and Parallel Computing Systems (PCS) research groups. Prof. de Laat chaired CCI since the split. His retirement is coming up later this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> is an experienced researcher, who is committed to lead CCI to a further successful future, leveraging his international research and teaching background and industrial leadership experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prof. de Laat and dr. Mann will continue to closely work together to make the transition as smooth as possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preference-Based Goal Refinement in BDI Agents</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/aamas_2022_mostafa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/aamas_2022_mostafa/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cost-optimized, data-protection-aware offloading between an edge data center and the cloud</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-cost-optimized-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-cost-optimized-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Decentralized application placement in fog computing</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-decentralized-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-decentralized-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dynamic generation of access control policies from social policies</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-dynamic-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-dynamic-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Promises and pitfalls of computational modelling for insurgency conflicts</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-der-zwet-promises-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-der-zwet-promises-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Security- and Privacy-Aware IoT Application Placement and User Assignment</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-security-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-security-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Algorithmic fog of war: When lack of transparency violates the law of armed conflict</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/kwik-algorithmic-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/kwik-algorithmic-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Computability of Diagrammatic Theories for Normative Positions</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/schweighofer-computability-2021-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/schweighofer-computability-2021-1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Computability of Diagrammatic Theories for Normative Positions</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/schweighofer-computability-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/schweighofer-computability-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Seamless Integration and Testing for MAS Engineering</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/emas_2021_mostafa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/emas_2021_mostafa/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Post-Quantum Cryptography: Challenges and Opportunities for Robust and Secure HW Design</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/bellizia-post-quantum-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/bellizia-post-quantum-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Accounting Value Effects for Responsible Networking</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/sileno-accounting-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/sileno-accounting-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>An Instruction Set Extension to Support Software-Based Masking</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/gao-instruction-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/gao-instruction-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Guest Editors’ Introduction: Special Issue on Top Picks in Hardware and Embedded Security</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/cammarota-guest-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/cammarota-guest-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Security, Reliability and Test Aspects of the RISC-V Ecosystem</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/abella-security-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/abella-security-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Smart contracts</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/de-filippi-smart-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/de-filippi-smart-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Special Section on Attacking and Protecting Artificial Intelligence</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/bhasin-special-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/bhasin-special-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Deeper Look at the Energy Consumption of Lightweight Block Ciphers</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/caforio-deeper-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/caforio-deeper-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Critical Reflection on ODRL</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/rodriguez-doncel-critical-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/rodriguez-doncel-critical-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Generic Back-End for Exploratory Programming</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/frolich-generic-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/frolich-generic-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Like Circles in the Water: Responsibility as a System-Level Function</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/rodriguez-doncel-like-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/rodriguez-doncel-like-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Solving Hofstadter’s Analogies Using Structural Information Theory</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/baratchi-solving-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/baratchi-solving-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Search for Symmetry in Hohfeldian Modalities</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/basu-search-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/basu-search-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Digital Enforceable Contracts (DEC): Making Smart Contracts Smarter</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/villata-digital-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/villata-digital-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Policy Enforcement for Secure and Trustworthy Data Sharing in Multi-domain Infrastructures</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-policy-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-policy-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A principled approach to REPL interpreters</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-principled-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-principled-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Declarative Preferences in Reactive BDI Agents</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/prima2020_mostafa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/prima2020_mostafa/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Run, Agent, Run! Architecture and Benchmark of Actor-based Agents</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/agere2020_mostafa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/agere2020_mostafa/</guid><description/></item><item><title>AgentScript Cross-Compiler</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/software/asc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/software/asc/</guid><description>&lt;p>The AgentScript Cross-Compiler (ASC) is an Agent-Oriented Programming Framework created to bridge the high-level abstraction power of AOP into modern development and deployment environments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AMdEX</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/project/amdex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/project/amdex/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Amsterdam Data Exchange aims to provide broad access to data for researchers, companies and private individuals. Inspired by the Open Science Cloud of the European Commission, the project is intended to connect with similar projects across Europe. And eventually even become part of a global movement to share data more easily.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eFlint</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/software/eflint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/software/eflint/</guid><description>&lt;p>Software systems that share potentially sensitive data are subjected to laws, regulations, policies and/or contracts. The monitoring, control and enforcement processes applied to these systems are currently to a large extent manual, which we rather automate by embedding the processes as dedicated and adaptable software services in order to improve efficiency and effectiveness. This approach requires such regulatory services to be closely aligned with a formal description of the relevant norms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>eFLINT&lt;/b> is a domain-specific language developed for formalizing norms from a variety of sources. The theoretical foundations of the language are found in transition systems and in Hohfeld’s framework of legal fundamental conceptions. The language can be used to formalize norms from a large variety of sources. The resulting specifications are executable and support several forms of reasoning such as automatic case assessment, manual exploration and simulation. Moreover, the specifications can be used to develop regulatory services for several types of monitoring, control and enforcement. The language is evaluated through a case study formalizing articles 6(1)(a) and 16 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). A prototype implementation of eflint is discussed and is available online &lt;a href="http://grotius.uvalight.net/eflintonline/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Erasmus+</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/project/erasmus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/project/erasmus/</guid><description/></item><item><title>FogProtect</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/project/fogprotect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/project/fogprotect/</guid><description/></item><item><title>SLICES</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/project/slices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/project/slices/</guid><description/></item><item><title>VISION</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/project/vision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/project/vision/</guid><description/></item><item><title>eFLINT: a domain-specific language for executable norm specifications</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-eflint-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-eflint-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Integrating Agent-Based Modelling with Copula Theory: Preliminary Insights and Open Problems</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/krzhizhanovskaya-integrating-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/krzhizhanovskaya-integrating-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Integrating CP-Nets in Reactive BDI Agents</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/prima2019_mostafa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/prima2019_mostafa/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Managing Effective Collaboration in Cybersecurity Alliances Using Social Computational Trust</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/deljoo-managing-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/deljoo-managing-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Big Data Platforms and Tools for Data Analytics in the Data Science Engineering Curriculum</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-big-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-big-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Open Data Market Architecture and Functional Components</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-open-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-open-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Designing Customisable Data Science Curriculum Using Ontology for Data Science Competences and Body of Knowledge</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-designing-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-designing-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>DL4LD</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/project/dl4ld/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/project/dl4ld/</guid><description>&lt;p>The DL4lD research project aims to help the Dutch logistics sector with digitalisation of their busines processes. To do so, DL4LD focuses on the trustworthy sharing of an organizations (potentially sensitive) data. Trust that the organization’s (potentially sensitive) data is handled in a controlled and secure way, is for many organizations a prerequisite sine qua non the organization may not be prepared to share its data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A focal point of the DL4LD research is on maintaining sovereignty by the data owner over the access, usage, processing and proliferation of his data DL4LD shows how to digitally support sufficient trust and sovereignty enablers to establish a trustworthy data sharing relationship between two logistic partners that didn&amp;rsquo;t have so a priori.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The DL4LD-project runs from January 2018 to December 2022.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EPI</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/project/epi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/project/epi/</guid><description>&lt;p>Knowledge is power &amp;ndash; and in healthcare, that holds absolutely true. Yet, for an industry that is under financial stress, increasing complexity of disease and co-morbidity, and burdened by capacity constraints &amp;ndash; why has data not been healthcare&amp;rsquo;s savvier? Three major challenges have inhibited this:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>data is not accessible and remains in silos;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>data is not analysed to derive meaningful clinical insights;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>insight isn&amp;rsquo;t accessible for actioning by providers or patients to self/joint manage their condition.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Our consortium of medical professionals, data scientists, IT-infrastructure experts, machine learning researchers and legal experts have designed Enabling Patient Interventions to liberate, analyse, and action that data in a trustworthy way. EPI aims to empower patients and providers through self-management, shared management, and personalization across the full health spectrum. To do so, we will build a fuller picture of the person by linking traditional eHealth data sets with new sources of data. Further, we will develop a platform based upon a secure and trustworthy distributed data infrastructure, combining data analytics, including machine learning, and health decision support algorithms to create new, actionable, and personalized insights for prevention, management, and intervention to providers and patients. We will develop new machine learning methods for determining and analysing optimal interventions within small patient groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our insights will be applied in healthcare use cases representing a spectrum of health management challenges ranging from common chronic to highly lethal orphan diseases, and will empower better self/joint management of these conditions to improve cost, quality, and outcomes of care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SSPDDP</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/project/sspddp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/project/sspddp/</guid><description>&lt;p>This proposal concerns multidisciplinary fundamental and applied research on developing a secure, end-to-end trusted, scalable and future-proof solution for distributed dynamic data sharing across multiple logistic domains. Sharing data across organizations in a secure, trusted and policy based manner, and enforcing the agreed use of that data is a hard problem. Many partial solutions already exist in the form of platforms, standards and directives, and back office solutions, all of them aimed at sharing data with their own goals and objectives. The absence of integrated solutions is hindering the potential exploitation of fused big data. Indeed, the research line “Data security in logistics” in the call underlines the importance of integrated cryptographically secure solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our proposal, typical logistics application profiles on specific demands in security, privacy, performance and policy will be identified. The goal of the proposed research is to develop end-to-end trusted and scalable solutions for typical application profiles that allow policy enforced data sharing and analysis across multiple IT domains based on negotiation of smart multi-party contracts. To achieve our goals, we will develop and integrate techniques for secure data sharing, scalability for big data, and policy-based data sharing and analytics. The ability to form temporary business alliances relies on the ability to implement ways to keep track of business agreements and transaction information in ways trusted by community members. The agility and diversity of market players, its data sources and potential risks if data is misused, is helped by creating a commonly trusted and governed infrastructure to access and share data. Such type of infrastructure is subject of research in Compartiment 1 of this call. In this proposal we will work alongside this work in order to investigate the value that blockchain technology will bring tosharing big data assets in a big data sharing infrastructure. The ability to provided trusted information from many distributed sources, such as mobile of tablet style devices that to not have to computational power to participate in traditional blockchain approaches, is an important topic address by this work. The aim is to not only protect primary data and limit accessibility via policy, but also to secure access to the provenance trails and other meta-data that are sensitive.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="the-main-goals-of-this-project-are">The main goals of this project are:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Prove the value of distribute block chain approaches that can be applied to logistic use-cases (provided by industry partners and compartment 1 collaborators)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide a future proof cryptographic approach considering the processing power quantum computing and other high performance compute technologies may bring.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide an environment allowing parties to create data sharing agreements compliant to the digital market place policy thus guaranteeing secure and trustworthy real time sharing of big data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide secure mechanisms for compliancy checking using provenance trails and audit trails, and mechanisms for dispute settlement in case of breaches.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cci-research.nl/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/home/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Humainer AI</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/project/humainer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/project/humainer/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>