<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Teaching in the Bachelor Information Science | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/category/teaching-in-the-bachelor-information-science/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/category/teaching-in-the-bachelor-information-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Teaching in the Bachelor Information Science</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Teaching in the Bachelor Information Science</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/category/teaching-in-the-bachelor-information-science/</link></image><item><title>Afstudeerproject BSc Informatiekunde</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/grad_project_bsc_ik/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/grad_project_bsc_ik/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this course Bachelor Information Science students setup and execute a research project exploring an Information Science related research topic under guidance of a researcher. The project results in a bachelor thesis, published in the UvA thesis database. The thesis project runs in period 2/3 as well as in period 5/6.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modelleren en Ontwerpen</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/modelleren_en_ontwerpen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/modelleren_en_ontwerpen/</guid><description>&lt;p>The course Modelling and Design is focused on learning domain modelling, and how to create formalised representation. Whilst applying modelling techniques, a broader architectural view is taken, in which students are made aware of choices in e.g. framing and scoping. This course prepares students to exchange knowledge with domain stakeholders, and to communicate potential design decisions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Organisatie: analyse en ontwikkeling</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/organisatie_analyse_en_ontwikkeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/organisatie_analyse_en_ontwikkeling/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the course Organisational Analysis and Developement (in Dutch Organisatieontwikkeling and -ontwikkeling) we study how collaborations between organisations influence IT-architectures that support cross-organisational collaboration. Particularly, we focus on data-sharing aspects and usage control that is required to create trust essential to collaboration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Netwerkorganisatie</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/netwerkorganisatie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/netwerkorganisatie/</guid><description>&lt;p>The course Network Organisation is focused on the questions why and how organisations collaborate in a complex environment. Studying those collaborations students are aimed to get better insights in how organisations function in a dynamic context. The students use system dynamic modelling to represent those collaborations and develop quantitative dynamic models that support policy decisions that affect the stakeholders in such complex enviroment&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>