<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Christopher Esterhuyse | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/christopher-esterhuyse/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/author/christopher-esterhuyse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Christopher Esterhuyse</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Christopher Esterhuyse</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/christopher-esterhuyse/</link></image><item><title>3 Papers Accepted at SPLASH 2024</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/splash-conf-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/splash-conf-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>Members of the &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Complex Cyber Infrastructure&lt;/a> group have been hard at work on the topic of software languages, developing methods and tools improving the productivity and control of programmers and language-designers.
The latest contributions are being published in three articles, which will each be presented at &lt;a href="https://2024.splashcon.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SPLASH 2024&lt;/a> in Pasadena, California.
Each contribution provides a piece of the puzzle of developing large and complex software systems:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Bridging Incremental Programming and Complex Software Development Environments
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>to be presented at &lt;a href="https://2024.splashcon.org/home/paint-2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PAINT&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>by Max Boksem and Thomas van Binsbergen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Summary: This article characterises and demonstrates a fundamentally graph-based programming environment: programs are built from explicitly-linked parts. This approach has benefits from two different, existing kinds of programming environment, which together make program parts easier to maintain and re-use.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Links: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3689488.3689991" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOI&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://ltvanbinsbergen.nl/files/papers/paint2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PRE-PRINT&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On the Soundness of Auto-completion Services for Dynamically Typed Languages
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>to be presented at &lt;a href="https://2024.splashcon.org/home/gpce-2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GPCE&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>by Damian Frölich and Thomas van Binsbergen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Summary: This article presents a novel mechanism for code editors to assist programmers by auto-suggesting identifiers. The novelty is that suggestions are based on an analysis of the program that is shallow enough to be fast and language-agnostic, but deep enough to guarantee suggestions are always valid.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Links: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3689484.3690734" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOI&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://ltvanbinsbergen.nl/files/papers/gpce2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PRE-PRINT&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cooperative Specification via Composition Control
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>to be presented at &lt;a href="https://2024.splashcon.org/track/sle-2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SLE&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>by Christopher Esterhuyse and Thomas van Binsbergen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Summary: This article presents a framework for using specification languages in a context where the specifications are developed from parts by cooperating agents. Some language features that are useful for this purpose are identified, and used to improve three existing specification languages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Links: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3687997.3695635" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOI&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://ltvanbinsbergen.nl/files/papers/sle2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PRE-PRINT&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>part of the &lt;a href="https://amdex.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AMdEX&lt;/a> project.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted at FORTE 2024</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/discotec24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/discotec24/</guid><description>&lt;p>On the 20th of June, Christopher Esterhuyse and Tim Mueller presented their paper (with L. Thomas van Binsbergen)
on the novel &lt;strong>JustAct&lt;/strong> framework at the &lt;a href="https://www.discotec.org/2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2024 DisCoTec&lt;/a> federated conference, held this year in Groningen.
JustAct lays a foundation for the automatic enforcement of policies that are changed by the users on the fly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Inter-organisational data exchange is regulated by norms originating from sources ranging from individual consent to (inter)national laws. Verifying norm-compliance is complex because laws (e.g., GDPR) distribute responsibility and require accountability. Moreover, in some domains (e.g., healthcare), the norms themselves may be private. In contrast, standard solutions (e.g., access- and usage-control, smart contracts) reason about policies that are assumed to be public. Instead, we present a novel framework prescribing how decentralised agents decide which actions are justified, despite their partial views of the policy. Crucially, justifications are universal, e.g., accepted by future auditors. Agents establish a common notion of compliance through an (externally synchronized) agreement, which is the basis of each justification defined by policy fragments agents autonomously create, gossip, and assemble.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programmeertalen</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/programmeertalen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/programmeertalen/</guid><description/></item><item><title>SNE Volleybal Team Outshines Competition</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/fnwi-volleybal-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/fnwi-volleybal-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Participating at the Faculty of Science&amp;rsquo;s annual volleybal tournament, Team
&lt;em>Snelle Jelle and the Daltons&lt;/em> featuring among others CCI members Tim, Damian,
Christopher and Marco, won the &lt;strong>Most Cheerful Outfit&lt;/strong> prize.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Out of the 16 teams participating, the &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5659248/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>The Daltons&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
look-alikes with fellow members of the MNS and PCS research groups from our SNE
cluster, managed to conquer the 11th place. A very nice result for the first
particpation, which we could not have achieved without our dedicated SNE
supporters that kept cheering for us until the very end. A special thanks to you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Read more about it in the Faculty&amp;rsquo;s staff website
&lt;a href="https://medewerker.uva.nl/en/science/content-secured/news/2023/05/faculty-volleyball-tournament-photanol-sils-wins-again.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>