<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yuri Demchenko | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/yuri-demchenko/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/author/yuri-demchenko/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Yuri Demchenko</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>Yuri Demchenko</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/yuri-demchenko/</link></image><item><title>SLICES-PP Receives Funding from the European Commission</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/slices-pp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/slices-pp/</guid><description>&lt;p>Scientific Large Scale Infrastructure for Computing/Communication
Experimental Studies -preparation project (SLICES-PP) is a project with
25 partners and a budget of 3 M€ for 4 years. The UvA will receive 303
K€ and it will be led by Yuri Demchenko of the Informatics Institute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Demchenko, from the CCI (Complex Cyber Infrastructure) group, will
coordinate two topics in SLICES-PP, first Research Data Management in
the SLICES infrastructure, and secondly SLICES capacity building and
career management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a part of activities in SLICES-PP, UvA will also facilitate creating
a SLICES-NL community and involving Dutch research organizations and
universities. The goal is to define the research agenda for SLICES-NL
and coordinate efforts to obtain national funding. In this connection,
new SLICES-NL coordination meetings will be organised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SLICES as a European Research Infrastructure aims to make a fundamental
contribution to research and innovation in digital sciences and
infrastructures, future Internet technologies, future smart networks and
services by providing high quality experimentation services with
emerging technologies around the area of digital sciences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new research infrastructure will allow academics and industry to
experiment and test future, possibly disruptive digital technologies,
essential for European research. This infrastructure can be beneficial
for other scientific and engineering domains, such as smart cities,
energy, green technologies and healthcare.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SLICES-PP will coordinate the preparatory stage to build the future
SLICES Research Infrastructure for Digital Technologies experimentation.
The project was submitted by consortium of 25 research institutions and
centers from 15 countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SLICES-RI (Research Infrastructure) is included in the ESFRI Roadmap
2021 as a new RI for digital technologies experimentation, together with
other already existing RI and e-Infrastructures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://slices-ri.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">More Information&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Big Data Platforms and Tools for Data Analytics in the Data Science Engineering Curriculum</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-big-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-big-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Open Data Market Architecture and Functional Components</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-open-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-open-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Designing Customisable Data Science Curriculum Using Ontology for Data Science Competences and Body of Knowledge</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-designing-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-designing-2019/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>