<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Softwares | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/software/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Softwares</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Softwares</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/software/</link></image><item><title>DYNAMOS</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/software/dynamos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/software/dynamos/</guid><description>&lt;p>The exchange of sensitive data is governed by numerous regulations and policies. Currently, many of the processes for monitoring and enforcing these regulations are performed manually. &lt;a href="https://github.com/DYNAMOS-UVA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DYNAMOS&lt;/a> (Dynamically Adaptive Microservice-based OS) is a data exchange middleware system that is designed to be self-adaptive, employing extensible algorithms to dynamically generate microservice compositions and select archetype patterns based on policy, user input, or system events. DYNAMOS makes use of sidecars for communication abstraction, protocol buffers for strict interface definition, and ephemeral single-use jobs for enhanced security as pivotal strategies. In conclusion, DYNAMOS demonstrates the potential for creating a more efficient and secure data exchange environment, enabling businesses and researchers to share information while maintaining control over their data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The original DYNAMOS paper can be found &lt;a href="https://github.com/Jorrit05/DYNAMOS/blob/main/docs/papers/architectural/ICSA_DYNAMOS_paper.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>. Demonstrations of DYNAMOS can be found &lt;a href="https://github.com/DYNAMOS-UVA#demonstrations--more-material" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AgentScript Cross-Compiler</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/software/asc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/software/asc/</guid><description>&lt;p>The AgentScript Cross-Compiler (ASC) is an Agent-Oriented Programming Framework created to bridge the high-level abstraction power of AOP into modern development and deployment environments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eFlint</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/software/eflint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/software/eflint/</guid><description>&lt;p>Software systems that share potentially sensitive data are subjected to laws, regulations, policies and/or contracts. The monitoring, control and enforcement processes applied to these systems are currently to a large extent manual, which we rather automate by embedding the processes as dedicated and adaptable software services in order to improve efficiency and effectiveness. This approach requires such regulatory services to be closely aligned with a formal description of the relevant norms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>eFLINT&lt;/b> is a domain-specific language developed for formalizing norms from a variety of sources. The theoretical foundations of the language are found in transition systems and in Hohfeld’s framework of legal fundamental conceptions. The language can be used to formalize norms from a large variety of sources. The resulting specifications are executable and support several forms of reasoning such as automatic case assessment, manual exploration and simulation. Moreover, the specifications can be used to develop regulatory services for several types of monitoring, control and enforcement. The language is evaluated through a case study formalizing articles 6(1)(a) and 16 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). A prototype implementation of eflint is discussed and is available online &lt;a href="http://grotius.uvalight.net/eflintonline/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>