<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cees de Laat | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Cees de Laat</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Cees de Laat</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/</link></image><item><title>UVA at Supercomputing 2025 in St. Louis</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/supercomputing-2025/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/supercomputing-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>We’re happy to share some highlights from the jointed participation of &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Complex Cyber Infrastructure&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://mns-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Multiscale Networked Systems&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://sc25.supercomputing.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Supercomputing 2025&lt;/a> in St Louis. The UVA team included &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/sander-klous/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sander Klous&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/anestisdalgkitsis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anestis Dalgitsis&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/alexandros-koufakis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alexandros Koufakis&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cees de Laat&lt;/a> (left to right on picture) and &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/profiel/g/r/p.grosso/p.grosso.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paola Grosso&lt;/a> (not pictured).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We showcased the results of two distinct research efforts. The first project, led by Anestis, focused on &lt;strong>LLM-Based Optimization Algorithm Selection for High-Performance Networks Orchestration&lt;/strong>. The second, led by Alexandros, demonstrated &lt;strong>Policy-aware Distributed Vertical Federated Learning infrastructure&lt;/strong>. Both works used the &lt;a href="https://portal.fabric-testbed.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FABRIC&lt;/a> testbed and live demonstrations took place at the &lt;a href="https://www.ciena.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CIENA&lt;/a> booth. The demonstrations used CIENA&amp;rsquo;s mobile FABRIC node (pictured above).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>LLM-Based Optimization&lt;/em> work was published and presented on the &lt;a href="https://scinet.supercomputing.org/community/indis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Innovating the Network for Data-Intensive Science&amp;rdquo; (INDIS)&lt;/em>&lt;/a> workshop. Both projects were featured on the &lt;a href="https://renci.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RENCI&lt;/a> booth as examples of innovative research enabled by the FABRIC infrastructure. Additionally, they were presented on the &lt;a href="https://scinethpc.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SciNet&lt;/a> theater on the exhibition floor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./Scinet_Anestis_presentation.jpg" alt="RENCI presentation">
&lt;em>Figure 1:&lt;/em> SciNet presentation — &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/anestisdalgkitsis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anestis Dalgkitsis&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./RENCI_Alexandros_presentation.jpg" alt="RENCI presentation">
&lt;em>Figure 2:&lt;/em> RENCI presentation — &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/alexandros-koufakis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alexandros Koufakis&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="llm-based-optimization-algorithm-selection-for-high-performance-networks-orchestration">LLM-Based Optimization Algorithm Selection for High-Performance Networks Orchestration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this work, we propose a Large Language Model (LLM)-based framework for optimization algorithm selection to address the growing complexity of high-performance, multi-domain network orchestration. The proposed solution introduces a context-aware abstraction layer where LLMs analyze network logs, service requests, and algorithm metadata to dynamically select the most suitable optimization strategy. We validate our framework through a prototype deployed on the FABRIC FAB international testbed and through simulations across diverse scenarios (eMBB, URLLC, mMTC, V2X, AR/VR), showing that LLM-driven selection achieves higher success rates and SLA compliance while balancing efficiency, accuracy, and inference latency. Our preliminary results demonstrate the feasibility of this method and highlight its potential to enable scalable, adaptive, and privacy-preserving orchestration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://delaat.net/sc/sc25/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paper and demonstration&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="policy-aware-distributed-vertical-federated-learning-infrastructure">Policy-aware distributed Vertical Federated Learning infrastructure &lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Harnessing the power of data is paramount to unlocking more effective applications, especially with the rise of machine learning. Data regulation, both through legislation and company policies, makes it impractical for different companies to learn from multiple datasets at once. Digital Data Marketplaces aim to solve this issue, by providing a platform where organizations can exchange data based on (dynamic) policies. The digital data marketplace enforces these policies, allowing only data exchange that does not violate policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this work we demonstration how multiple geographically distributed companies can train a unified machine learning model collaboratively using Vertical Federated Learning. Towards this goal we designed and implemented &lt;a href="https://github.com/DYNAMOS-UVA/Scattered-Directive" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Scattered Directive&lt;/a>, a state-of-the-art distributed infrastructure deployment utilizing FABRIC, capable of automatically deploying a digital data marketplace platform. Scattered Directive is built ontop of &lt;a href="https://github.com/DYNAMOS-UVA/DYNAMOS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DYNAMOS&lt;/a>, a middleware for datachange systems. Moreover, we demonstrate the effect of dynamic data sharing policies and the impact on the universal model training.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://delaat.net/sc/sc25/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Demonstration&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://github.com/DYNAMOS-UVA/.github/blob/main/Demonstration_material/SC_2025/SC2025.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener">More material&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">Acknowledgements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We would like to thank &lt;a href="https://www.ciena.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CIENA&lt;/a> for their support. &lt;a href="https://renci.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RENCI&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://scinethpc.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SciNet&lt;/a> for hosting our demonstrations. Finally, we would like to acknowledge that part of this work was supported by the project: &lt;a href="https://www.prets.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Budget-neutral sustainable home improvements (MOOI-224049)&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UVA at Supercomputing 2024 in Atlanta</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/supercomputing-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/supercomputing-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>We’re thrilled to share highlights from the jointed participation of &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Complex Cyber Infrastructure&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://mns-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Multiscale Networked Systems&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://sc24.supercomputing.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Supercomputing 2024&lt;/a> in Atlanta, where we demonstrated our research on microservices-based collaborative model training on the &lt;a href="https://portal.fabric-testbed.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FABRIC&lt;/a> testbed infrastructure. The UVA team included &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/alexandros-koufakis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alexandros Koufakis&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/anestisdalgkitsis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anestis Dalgitsis&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cees de Laat&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/profiel/g/r/p.grosso/p.grosso.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paola Grosso&lt;/a> (left to right on picture).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Monday at INDIS 2024:&lt;/strong>
We kicked off the week by presenting our work at the &lt;a href="https://scinet.supercomputing.org/community/indis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INDIS&lt;/a> 2024 workshop, held on November 18. Our &lt;a href="https://github.com/Jorrit05/DYNAMOS/blob/main/docs/papers/federated_learning/INDIS_2024_Short_Paper_Final_v2_1_45.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">paper&lt;/a>, “Microservices-based FABRIC Implementation of Collaborative Model Training Scenario with Vertical Federated Learning,” tackled the challenge of using geographically distributed proprietary data for collaborative AI model training while adhering to data privacy and protection.
Using the &lt;a href="https://github.com/Jorrit05/DYNAMOS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DYNAMOS&lt;/a> middleware and the FABRIC network, we demonstrated how the problem of building energy consumption prediction (inspired by our collaborators &lt;a href="https://www.prets.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prets&lt;/a>) can be addressed using a diverse set of partners. Participants with heterogeneous datasets can collaborate to create a unified model for prediction building energy consumption, without compromising privacy or intellectual property. This solution could reinforce green energy adoption and enable more economically viable building renovation financing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./INDIS_presentation.jpg" alt="INDIS presentation">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tuesday on the SCinet Stage:&lt;/strong>
On November 19, we took to the SCinet Theater on the exhibition floor to show our ideas in action. Our &lt;a href="https://delaat.net/sc/sc24/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">demo&lt;/a> featured the FABRIC network&amp;rsquo;s topology and showcased how Vertical Federated Learning could be used to train a model that predicts energy consumption while protecting sensitive data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./SciNet_presentation.jpg" alt="SciNet presentation">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Exhibition Floor Action:&lt;/strong>
Until Thursday, November 21, we were hosted at &lt;a href="https://www.ciena.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CIENA’s&lt;/a> booth, where we continued to showcase our demonstration and connect with visitors from around the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Acknowledgements:&lt;/strong>
We couldn’t have done this without the support from &lt;a href="https://www.ciena.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CIENA&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.prets.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prets&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Governance</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/theme/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/theme/governance/</guid><description>&lt;p>The research in this theme addresses several challenges that arise from modern service-oriented systems in which the development and operationalisation of (software) services is distributed across organisational domains. These systems have in common that parties may play different roles in the realisation of applications, e.g., providing a service (such as creating data insights), infrastructure (such as compute or storage resources), or assets (such as datasets and algorithms). In such systems, organisations wish to retain control over the usage of their resources, e.g., to limit their availability, adhere to (privacy) regulations, or to protect commercial interests. To give control to resource owners, we propose systems in which policies are used to express usage constraints, mechanisms are available to enforce these constraints, and monitoring provides the information necessary for making enforcement decisions. Data exchange systems and digital data marketplaces are the primary application context, providing motivation and specific case studies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Particular challenges addressed by our work are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The expression of laws, regulations, organisational policies and contractual agreements as enforceable system-level policies. This requires policy languages bridging the gap between legal statements and system-level events and distributed usage control mechanisms for policy enforcement.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The distribution of control itself: different stakeholders (users, resource owners) contribute parts of the policy and control mechanisms (besides their contribution to the application itself). How can the policies expressed at location A affect decisions made at location B, considering the desire to avoid centralisation and considering that policies themselves may be sensitive?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The automatic integration of formalised interpretations of legal sources places demands on the underlying enforcement mechanisms. Firstly, ex-post enforcement (observing and responding to violations after their occurrence) is required as not all information may be available or (interpretations of) legal sources may be conflicting. Secondly, policy decisions need to be accountable such that information on which these decisions are based (policies, meta-data, actual data) may need to be retained and may themselves by sensitive.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Compliance-by-design. How and to what extent can we schedule the execution of applications or reconfigure the system&amp;rsquo;s configuration to ensure compliance with identified policy requirements.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In this research theme we develop conceptual models, algorithms, protocols, languages and (prototype) tools that address these challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="projects">Projects&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/project/amdex">&lt;img src="https://cci-research.nl/project/amdex/featured.png" width=200 style="display: inline;" />&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/project/dl4ld">&lt;img src="https://cci-research.nl/project/dl4ld/featured.jpg" width=200 style="display: inline;" />&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi">&lt;img src="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi/featured.png" width=200 style="display: inline;" />&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/project/sspddp">&lt;img src="https://cci-research.nl/project/sspddp/featured.png" width=200 style="display: inline;" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="software">Software&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/software/eflint/">&lt;img src="https://cci-research.nl/software/eflint/featured.png" width=200 style="display: inline;"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/software/asc/">&lt;img src="https://cci-research.nl/software/asc/featured.png" width=200 style="display: inline;"/>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="publications">Publications&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="2025">2025&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/gpce2025/" >A Stable Model Semantics for eFLINT Norm Specifications and Model Checking Scenarios.&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/christopher-esterhuyse/">Christopher Esterhuyse&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/">L. Thomas van Binsbergen&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tim-muller/">Tim Müller&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/gpce2025/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/amdex/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3742876.3742882" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="2024">2024&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/just-act-2024/" >JustAct: Actions Universally Justified by Partial Dynamic Policies&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/christopher-esterhuyse/">Christopher Esterhuyse&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tim-muller/">Tim Müller&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/">L. Thomas van Binsbergen&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/just-act-2024/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/amdex/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/dmi/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-62645-6_4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-031-62645-6_4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/oasics-epi-2024/" >Building a Digital Health Twin for Personalized Intervention: The EPI Project.&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/milen-girma-kebede/">Milen Girma Kebede&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tim-muller/">Tim Müller&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/">L. Thomas van Binsbergen&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/">Cees de Laat&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/sander-klous/">Sander Klous&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.4230/OASIcs.Commit2Data.2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2023">2023&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-2023/" >Enabling Collaborative Multi-Domain Applications: A Blockchain-Based Solution with Petri Net Workflow Modeling and Incentivization&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/reginald-cushing/">Reginald Cushing&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/xin-zhou/">Xin Zhou&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/adam-belloum/">Adam Belloum&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/paola-grosso/">Paola Grosso&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tom-van-engers/">Tom van Engers&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/">Cees de Laat&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/zhou-2023/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/dl4ld/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1109/TPS-ISA58951.2023.00036" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10431649" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/alsayed-kassem-2022/" >Utilisation Profiles of Bridging Function Chain for Healthcare Use Cases&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/jamila-alsayed-kassem/">Jamila Alsayed Kassem&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/adam-belloum/">Adam Belloum&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tim-muller/">Tim Müller&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/paola-grosso/">Paola Grosso&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/alsayed-kassem-2022/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1109/eScience55777.2022.00085" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9973638" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2022">2022&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/alsayed-kassem-2022/" >Utilisation Profiles of Bridging Function Chain for Healthcare Use Cases&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/jamila-alsayed-kassem/">Jamila Alsayed Kassem&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/adam-belloum/">Adam Belloum&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tim-muller/">Tim Müller&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/paola-grosso/">Paola Grosso&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/alsayed-kassem-2022/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1109/eScience55777.2022.00085" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9973638" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/mohajeri-parizi-2022/" >A Modular Architecture for Integrating Normative Advisors in MAS&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/mostafa-mohajeri-parizi/">Mostafa Mohajeri Parizi&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/">L. Thomas van Binsbergen&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/giovanni-sileno/">Giovanni Sileno&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tom-van-engers/">Tom van Engers&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/mohajeri-parizi-2022/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/amdex/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/dl4ld/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1109/eScience55777.2022.00086" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-031-20614-6_18" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/salt-lake-city-2022/" >Exploring the Enforcement of Private, Dynamic Policies on Medical Workflow Execution&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/christopher-esterhuyse/">Christopher Esterhuyse&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tim-muller/">Tim Müller&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/">L. Thomas van Binsbergen&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/adam-belloum/">Adam Belloum&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/salt-lake-city-2022/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/amdex/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1109/eScience55777.2022.00086" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9973688" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2021">2021&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhang-2021/" >Profiling and Discriminating of Containerized ML Applications in Digital Data Marketplaces (DDM)&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/lu-zhang/">Lu Zhang&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/reginald-cushing/">Reginald Cushing&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/ralph-koning/">Ralph Koning&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/">Cees de Laat&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/paola-grosso/">Paola Grosso&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/zhang-2021/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.5220/0010254105080515" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://www.scitepress.org/Link.aspx?doi=10.5220/0010254105080515" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-dynamic-2022/" >Dynamic generation of access control policies from social policies&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/">L. Thomas van Binsbergen&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/milen-girma-kebede/">Milen Girma Kebede&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/joshua-baugh/">Joshua Baugh&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tom-van-engers/">Tom van Engers&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/dannis-g.-van-vuurden/">Dannis G. van Vuurden&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/van-binsbergen-dynamic-2022/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.procs.2021.12.221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S1877050921024601" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/valkering-2021/" >Brane: A Framework for Programmable Orchestration of Multi-Site Applications&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/onno-valkering/">Onno Valkering&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/reginald-cushing/">Reginald Cushing&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/adam-belloum/">Adam Belloum&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/valkering-2021/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1109/eScience51609.2021.00056" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9582292" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/alsayed-kassem-2021/" >EPI Framework: Approach for Traffic Redirection Through Containerised Network Functions&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/jamila-alsayed-kassem/">Jamila Alsayed Kassem&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/onno-valkering/">Onno Valkering&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/adam-belloum/">Adam Belloum&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/paola-grosso/">Paola Grosso&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/alsayed-kassem-2021/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi/">
Project
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1109/eScience51609.2021.00018" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9582400" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2020">2020&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-policy-2020/" >Policy Enforcement for Secure and Trustworthy Data Sharing in Multi-domain Infrastructures&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/xin-zhou/">Xin Zhou&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/reginald-cushing/">Reginald Cushing&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/ralph-koning/">Ralph Koning&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/adam-belloum/">Adam Belloum&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/paola-grosso/">Paola Grosso&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/sander-klous/">Sander Klous&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tom-van-engers/">Tom van Engers&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/">Cees de Laat&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/zhou-policy-2020/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1109/BigDataSE50710.2020.00022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9343348/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="media stream-item">
&lt;div class="media-body">
&lt;h3 class="article-title mb-0 mt-0">
&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-eflint-2020/" >eFLINT: a domain-specific language for executable norm specifications&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="stream-meta article-metadata">
&lt;div>
&lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/">L. Thomas van Binsbergen&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/lu-chi-liu/">Lu-Chi Liu&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/robert-van-doesburg/">Robert van Doesburg&lt;/a>&lt;/span>, &lt;span >&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tom-van-engers/">Tom van Engers&lt;/a>&lt;/span>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="btn-links">
&lt;button type="button" class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm js-cite-modal"
data-filename="/publication/van-binsbergen-eflint-2020/cite.bib">
Cite
&lt;/button>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3425898.3426958" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
DOI
&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="btn btn-outline-primary my-1 mr-1 btn-sm" href="https://dare.uva.nl/search?identifier=bb19cb35-c43e-4d70-81c9-8b6d3bdaa091" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
URL
&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ml-3">
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Digital Health Twin for Personalized Intervention: The EPI Project.</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/oasics-epi-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/oasics-epi-2024/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @IEEE TPS 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-tps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-tps/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>Enabling Collaborative Multi-Domain Applications: A Blockchain-Based Solution with Petri Net Workflow Modeling and Incentivization&lt;/b> by Zhou, X., Cushing, R., Koning, R., Belloum, A., Grosso, P., Klous, S., van Engers, T. &amp; de Laat, C. was accepted at &lt;a
http://www.sis.pitt.edu/lersais/conference/tps/2023/">The Fifth IEEE International Conference on Trust, Privacy and Security in Intelligent Systems, and Applications&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The increasing value of data and the emergence of programmable infrastructures have paved the way for collaborative multi-domain applications across industries such as healthcare and airlines. However, such collaborations come with significant challenges, including application coordination, incentivization, and validation of execution. In this paper, we propose a novel solution that leverages blockchain technology and utilizes Petri nets for workflow modeling. Our approach involves implementing a smart contract-based workflow coordinator on the blockchain and employing a three-layered architecture to coordinate off-chain tasks. Additionally, we demonstrate the use of Petri nets for modeling economy tokens, which serve as incentives to foster collaboration among workflow parties. To validate our solution, we present a proof of concept through a simulated use case involving a multi-domain workflow for mitigating a DDoS attack. In this use case, domains collaborate by blocking offending IPs, incentivized by acquired tokens required to invoke workflows.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Published@AMC 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-published-amc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-published-amc/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>The dynamics of corruption under an optional external supervision service&lt;/b> by Xin Zhou, Adam Belloum, Michael H. Lees, Tom van Engers, Cees de Laat has been published at &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0096300323003417">Applied Mathematics and Computation&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>External supervision services play an important role in combating corruption by detecting potential collusive bribery. This work aims at studying the dynamics of collusive bribery when participants have the option of engaging the external supervision services. To do so, we construct a basic model where collusive bribery can happen between the defecting participants who aim to escape from a punishment by offering a bribe to rule enforcers who monitor interactions among all participants. Among rule enforcers, only the corrupt ones accept the bribe and ignore the violations. The cooperative participants can engage the external supervision service at a certain cost to avoid the risk of potential collusive bribery. Under the framework of evolutionary game theory, we find that a higher initial fraction of honest enforcers is more likely to lead to a trusting cooperating equilibrium. We also find that, when allowing random exploration of available strategies, increasing the exploration rate of rule enforcers is effective in combating corruption for both infinite and finite populations. Lastly, we find that minimizing the cost of external supervision services is not always good. When the system evolves into a cooperating equilibrium, a low cost of external supervision service induces unnecessary costs of seeking external supervision. When the strategy profiles exhibit stable oscillations, there exists an optimal cost of external supervision, considering the trade-off between minimizing the chance of exposing cooperative participants to collusive bribery and strengthening the punishment on the corrupt enforcers. Premised on the results, we discuss practical management suggestions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enabling Collaborative Multi-Domain Applications: A Blockchain-Based Solution with Petri Net Workflow Modeling and Incentivization</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Symposium in honor of Cees de Laat and Leon Gommans</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/symposium-cees-leon-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/symposium-cees-leon-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>A symposium entitled &lt;strong>‘From Systems and Networks to Complex Cyber Infrastructures’&lt;/strong> took place on 9th December 2022 in honor of Cees de Laat and Leon Gommans.
On the one hand, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cees de Laat&lt;/a>, the former Chair of CCI, retired recently.
This symposium looked at where the systems, networking and complex cyber infrastructures field stands today, a field to which Cees has contributed greatly.
On the other hand, the symposium celebrated &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/leon-gommans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leon Gommans&lt;/a> for becoming Professor by Special Appointment in the area of Complex Cyber Infrastructure for Data Exchange Systems within CCI.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="an-afternoon-with-a-lot-of-insights-personal-memories-and-fun">An afternoon with a lot of insights, personal memories, and fun&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Turing Zaal in Amsterdam Science Park was packed with people, some of whom came from other continents to salute Cees and Leon on this special occasion.
The audience enjoyed talks by a lineup of distinguished speakers.
The symposium was opened by &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/profiel/g/r/p.grosso/p.grosso.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paola Grosso&lt;/a> from the Multiscale Networked Systems group.
In the first talk, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/leon-gommans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leon Gommans&lt;/a> explained how multi-domain authorization research evolved into data exchange systems research.
Leon was followed by &lt;a href="https://crd.lbl.gov/divisions/amcr/about-amcr/staff/computer-science/john-shalf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John Shalf&lt;/a>, Department Head for Computer Science at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, who talked about the future of computing beyond exascale.
The first session ended with a very personal talk by &lt;a href="https://www.vuhpdc.net/henri-bal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Henri Bal&lt;/a> from Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, entitled &amp;ldquo;Networking with Cees&amp;rdquo;.
After the break, Dutch Internet pioneer &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kees_Neggers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kees Neggers&lt;/a> took the floor with a historical overview from ARPANET to complex cyber infrastructures.
In the sequel, the second speaker from the USA, &lt;a href="https://www.sdsc.edu/research/researcher_spotlight/wuerthwein_frank.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Frank Würthwein&lt;/a>, Director of the San Diego Supercomputer Center, focused on the future of open research platforms.
The last talk was given by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cees de Laat&lt;/a>, who shared several insights as well as numerous funny and memorable moments from his career.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The symposium, which was organized by the &lt;a href="https://mns-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Multiscale Networked Systems&lt;/a> group, the &lt;a href="https://pcs-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Parallel Computing Systems&lt;/a> group, and CCI, ended with a reception, giving the attendants the opportunity to meet old and new friends.
For sure, this afternoon will be a pleasant and inspiring memory for the people who had the honor to be present.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visit of Inder Monga</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/visit-indermonga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/visit-indermonga/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week we had a visit from Inder Monga, director ESnet, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. In this visit we had many discussions on the already 2 decades of working together on different advanced networking topics. In particular we are starting up cooperation on Quantum Networking and we are a partner in the experimental networks testbed &lt;a href="https://www.whatisfabric.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FABRIC&lt;/a>, where &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">prof. de Laat&lt;/a> serves on the Scientific Advisory Board. FABRIC (FABRIC is Adaptive ProgrammaBle Research Infrastructure for Computer Science and Science Applications) is an International infrastructure that enables cutting-edge experimentation and research at-scale in the areas of networking, cybersecurity, distributed computing, storage, virtual reality, 5G, machine learning, and science applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later this year (components shortage permitting) we will receive a FABRIC node in Amsterdam for our students and researchers to experiment on with our programmable networks and data exchange research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Friday July 8th Inder presented a colloquium with the title:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ESnet: Advancing networking for Science and the science of Networking&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Abstract&lt;/em>: Research and Education networks play a key role in providing the
data infrastructure to accelerate scientific discovery. This talk will discuss
how the leading Department of Energy user facility in the United States,
ESnet, contributes to scientific discovery and the set of network research
activities including quantum networking currently in progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Biographical Sketch&lt;/em>: Inder Monga provides research and technology
direction, actively leads research projects and manages software engineering
efforts for ESnet. He focuses on advancing networking services for
accelerating collaborative and distributed science, as well as contributes
actively to efforts in the industry related to Software-Defined Networking,
Science DMZ, performance management as well as the Advanced Network
Testbed Initiatives. He is appointed as the chair of ONF&amp;rsquo;s Research
Associates, and contributes actively to the Global Network Architecture
activity. Monga’s research interests include network virtualization, software-
defined networking, grid/cloud computing and sensor networking, and he
holds 17 granted patents. His work experience in the private sector has
included software development, research and network engineering for
Wellfleet Communications and Nortel, where he focused on application and
network convergence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Costly incentives design from an institutional perspective: cooperation, sustainability and affluence</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/proceeding_a_xin_2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/proceeding_a_xin_2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Change of Group Leadership</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</guid><description>&lt;p>As of 1 June 2022, leadership of the Complex Cyber Infrastructure research group was transferred from Prof. Cees de Laat to Dr. Zoltan Mann.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof.dr.ir. Cees de Laat&lt;/a> chaired the System and Network Engineering (SNE) research group since 2006. SNE became so large that on his proposal it was split into three successful research groups in 2020: Complex Cyber Infrastructure (CCI), the Multiscale Networked Systems (MNS), and Parallel Computing Systems (PCS) research groups. Prof. de Laat chaired CCI since the split. His retirement is coming up later this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> is an experienced researcher, who is committed to lead CCI to a further successful future, leveraging his international research and teaching background and industrial leadership experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prof. de Laat and dr. Mann will continue to closely work together to make the transition as smooth as possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Profiling and Discriminating of Containerized ML Applications in Digital Data Marketplaces (DDM)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhang-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhang-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Policy Enforcement for Secure and Trustworthy Data Sharing in Multi-domain Infrastructures</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-policy-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-policy-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Managing Effective Collaboration in Cybersecurity Alliances Using Social Computational Trust</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/deljoo-managing-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/deljoo-managing-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Open Data Market Architecture and Functional Components</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-open-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-open-2019/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>