<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cees de Laat | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Cees de Laat</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>Cees de Laat</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/</link></image><item><title>Visit of Inder Monga</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/visit-indermonga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/visit-indermonga/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week we had a visit from Inder Monga, director ESnet, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. In this visit we had many discussions on the already 2 decades of working together on different advanced networking topics. In particular we are starting up cooperation on Quantum Networking and we are a partner in the experimental networks testbed &lt;a href="https://www.whatisfabric.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FABRIC&lt;/a>, where &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">prof. de Laat&lt;/a> serves on the Scientific Advisory Board. FABRIC (FABRIC is Adaptive ProgrammaBle Research Infrastructure for Computer Science and Science Applications) is an International infrastructure that enables cutting-edge experimentation and research at-scale in the areas of networking, cybersecurity, distributed computing, storage, virtual reality, 5G, machine learning, and science applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later this year (components shortage permitting) we will receive a FABRIC node in Amsterdam for our students and researchers to experiment on with our programmable networks and data exchange research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Friday July 8th Inder presented a colloquium with the title:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ESnet: Advancing networking for Science and the science of Networking&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Abstract&lt;/em>: Research and Education networks play a key role in providing the
data infrastructure to accelerate scientific discovery. This talk will discuss
how the leading Department of Energy user facility in the United States,
ESnet, contributes to scientific discovery and the set of network research
activities including quantum networking currently in progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Biographical Sketch&lt;/em>: Inder Monga provides research and technology
direction, actively leads research projects and manages software engineering
efforts for ESnet. He focuses on advancing networking services for
accelerating collaborative and distributed science, as well as contributes
actively to efforts in the industry related to Software-Defined Networking,
Science DMZ, performance management as well as the Advanced Network
Testbed Initiatives. He is appointed as the chair of ONF&amp;rsquo;s Research
Associates, and contributes actively to the Global Network Architecture
activity. Monga’s research interests include network virtualization, software-
defined networking, grid/cloud computing and sensor networking, and he
holds 17 granted patents. His work experience in the private sector has
included software development, research and network engineering for
Wellfleet Communications and Nortel, where he focused on application and
network convergence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change of Group Leadership</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</guid><description>&lt;p>As of 1 June 2022, leadership of the Complex Cyber Infrastructure research group was transferred from Prof. Cees de Laat to Dr. Zoltan Mann.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof.dr.ir. Cees de Laat&lt;/a> chaired the System and Network Engineering (SNE) research group since 2006. SNE became so large that on his proposal it was split into three successful research groups in 2020: Complex Cyber Infrastructure (CCI), the Multiscale Networked Systems (MNS), and Parallel Computing Systems (PCS) research groups. Prof. de Laat chaired CCI since the split. His retirement is coming up later this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> is an experienced researcher, who is committed to lead CCI to a further successful future, leveraging his international research and teaching background and industrial leadership experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prof. de Laat and dr. Mann will continue to closely work together to make the transition as smooth as possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Policy Enforcement for Secure and Trustworthy Data Sharing in Multi-domain Infrastructures</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-policy-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-policy-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Managing Effective Collaboration in Cybersecurity Alliances Using Social Computational Trust</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/deljoo-managing-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/deljoo-managing-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Open Data Market Architecture and Functional Components</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-open-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/demchenko-open-2019/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>