<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Posts</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>Posts</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/</link></image><item><title>Master Software Engineering student papers accepted at BENEVOL’22</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/papers-accepted-at-benevol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/papers-accepted-at-benevol/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bas van den Brink’s work on applying model-based testing to microservices has been accepted as a proceedings contribution to &lt;a href=
"https://benevol2022.github.io/">BENEVOL’22&lt;/a>. He is supervised by Ana Oprescu, Tannaz Zameni (University of Twente), Lammert Vinke (Info Support), and Dr. Ulyana Tikhonova (Axini). This project is of particular interest to the &lt;a href="https://www.versen.nl/contents/works/masters-thesis-projects">VERSEN Master’s Thesis Projects Working Group&lt;/a> as an example of multi-university multi-industry collaboration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anjali Ahlawat’s work on a practical maintainability model for data models has also been accepted as a presentation abstract. She is supervised by Ana Oprescu, and two SIG supervisors, Xander Schrijen, and Bugra M. Yildiz.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ana Oprescu on Travelling as a Mom</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-traveling-as-a-mom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-traveling-as-a-mom/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wrote this short piece about travelling with my baby. My point with this, is to bring attention to a compromise parents might not have to make anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Work traveling with Maria.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my home country, mothers can spend up to two years of almost fully paid maternal leave. The Netherlands, with their 16 weeks is a far cry. Luckily, my husband, a freelancing mathematician, can travel with me and take care of Maria while I am participating in the various work activities. As such, Maria has already joined the Nijmegen SusTrainable Teacher Training before she had turned 1, and then joined ICT4S and the SusTrainable summer school. It has not been easy, and the EU does not help in any way, but the UvA is a great employer in this sense, and I can focus much better while traveling for work, knowing I will join Maria in the late afternoon, as if a normal day at ‘home’.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ana Oprescu will join as co-chair the Amsterdam Data Science Thesis Award PC</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/anna-join-ds-award/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/anna-join-ds-award/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please send your Bachelor and/or Master thesis nominations &lt;a href="https://amsterdamdatascience.nl/news/2022-ads-thesis-awards/#:~:text=Amsterdam%20Data%20Science%20(ADS)%20is,the%208th%20of%20December%202022">here&lt;/a>. There is a special second track supporting diversity. Contact Ana at a.m.oprescu[at]uva.nl for any questions or clarifications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Presentation by Ana Oprescu @ICT4S</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-presented-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-presented-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ana Oprescu presented her &lt;a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9830083/">paper&lt;/a> on the Energy Cost and Accuracy of K-anonymity in &lt;a href="https://conf.researchr.org/series/ict4s">ICT4S&lt;/a> (Mon 13 - Fri 17 June 2022 Plovdiv, Bulgaria).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
​​European Union has aggregated the current societal concerns into two seemingly orthogonal directions: the Green Deal and the GDPR. In this paper, we begin to analyse trade-offs in preserving privacy, learning from the data, and saving energy. Considerable research studied the energy efficiency of software and the accuracy of machine learning models trained on anonymised datasets. However, to the best of our knowledge, no research has been conducted on the impact of anonymisation techniques on energy consumption. We measure the impact of anonymisation on the energy consumption and on the accuracy of machine learning models.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
We find that the k-value has a statistically significant impact on the energy consumption of the chosen anonymization algorithms. In terms of the accuracy of machine learning models, the generalisation and suppression performs better in almost all cases, provided that proper anonymization hierarchies are used in the anonymization process. However, we find that for the larger and more complex dataset, the reduction in accuracy is limited while there is a significant difference in energy consumption. Thus when considering energy consumption we conclude that for larger datasets it might be worthwhile to consider using microaggregation over generalisation and suppression.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the same event, Lukas Koedijk also presented the &lt;a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9830107/">paper&lt;/a> co-authored with Ana Oprescu based on his master graduation project on the Energy Footprint of Programming Languages. Lukas is an alumnus of the Software Engineering master, now working at KPMG.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The EU Green Deal mirrors the societal concern regarding climate change. In the software industry this means reducing the energy consumption of a program. This can be done by looking both at the hardware and the software used. We take a software approach and focus on the programming language choices and how a computer program is written. The programming languages we investigate are Java, JavaScript, Python, PHP, Ruby, C, C++ and C#. We compare programs from The Computer Language Benchmarks Game and these programs are divided in groups that solve the same problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We find that the choice of programming language and the way of writing your program influences the energy consumption. The programming languages that consume the least amount of energy over all the problems are C and C++, albeit these programming languages consume more energy when compilation flags are minimized. However, in some cases we could not prove that there was a difference in the energy consumption. We also find that the hardware used to run the programs has an influence on the energy consumption. We find that the runtime of a program correlates with the energy consumption, but a shorter runtime does not necessarily result in a lower energy consumption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the colocated &lt;a href="https://gsd.web.elte.hu/events/sustrainable">SusTrainable workshop&lt;/a>, Ana also presented current research efforts on Energy-driven Software Engineering. The workshop was organised by the Erasmus+ project &lt;a href="https://sustrainable.github.io/">SusTrainable&lt;/a>, in which UvA is a partner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The EU Climate Law targets climate neutrality by 2050. At the same time, the Knowledge Economy is deemed crucial to EU prosperity. Thus, the energy footprint of software services remains an important topic of research and education. In these lecture notes, we set out to educate students on energy-aware software engineering. We show how to establish whether some programming languages are inherently more “green”. We also show how to assess whether established software smells (anti-patterns) are also energy-related smells.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Software Engineering master student Nuria Bruch wins VERSEN Master Thesis Award!</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/nuria-versen-award/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/nuria-versen-award/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nuria Bruch, supervised by Ana Oprescu, Miroslav Zivkovic and Lodewijk Bergmans wins the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sig_eu/status/1525150139614171138">VERSEN Master Thesis Award&lt;/a> for her work on &lt;a href="https://zenodo.org/record/4280883#.YtqQxdJByV5">measuring the degree of library dependency!&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The usage of libraries, both commercial and open-source, encapsulating the implementation of certain functionalities is a widespread practice among developers. However, when a developer uses a library in a software product, this creates a dependency, and if a library has a security issue, it can be propagated to the software product. Developers can use package managers, however, these generally offer a simple binary evaluation of the dependencies: either there is one or not. Hence, a detailed evaluation of the dependencies is missing, which could help developers deal with vulnerabilities, breaking changes, and deprecated dependencies. Nuria proposes a model for software dependencies, which can help provide a fine-grained evaluation of them. The model includes three types of metrics: coupling, coverage, and usage per class. For each metric in the model, Nuria provides a formal definition and a theoretical validation by proving the metrics’ properties. She additionally implemented a proof-of-concept tool that, given a library from the Maven Central Repository, calculates the metrics of the model for each of the dependencies using bytecode analysis. Moreover, the proof-of-concept includes a visualisation of the dependency tree, including the calculated metrics. Finally, she conducted experiments to validate the model, the implementation of the proof-of-concept, and the visualisation. The experiments include interviews with 15 professional developers who evaluated the clarity and actionability of the model’s metrics and the proposed visualisations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SusTrainable summer school</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-presented-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-presented-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>During the &lt;a href="https://sustrainable.uniri.hr/">Rijeka SusTrainable summer school&lt;/a> (4-8 July 2022, Rijeka, Croatia) organised by the Erasmus+ project SusTrainable Ana Oprescu gave a lecture on the methodologies employed for Energy-driven Software Engineering research. This was followed by a hands-on session prepared together with Kyrian Maat and based on work by Lukas Koedijk, Stephan Kok and Sander van Oostveen. The school was well attended by UvA master and PhD students, as well as junior lecturers.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visit of Inder Monga</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/visit-indermonga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/visit-indermonga/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week we had a visit from Inder Monga, director ESnet, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. In this visit we had many discussions on the already 2 decades of working together on different advanced networking topics. In particular we are starting up cooperation on Quantum Networking and we are a partner in the experimental networks testbed &lt;a href="https://www.whatisfabric.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FABRIC&lt;/a>, where &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">prof. de Laat&lt;/a> serves on the Scientific Advisory Board. FABRIC (FABRIC is Adaptive ProgrammaBle Research Infrastructure for Computer Science and Science Applications) is an International infrastructure that enables cutting-edge experimentation and research at-scale in the areas of networking, cybersecurity, distributed computing, storage, virtual reality, 5G, machine learning, and science applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later this year (components shortage permitting) we will receive a FABRIC node in Amsterdam for our students and researchers to experiment on with our programmable networks and data exchange research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Friday July 8th Inder presented a colloquium with the title:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ESnet: Advancing networking for Science and the science of Networking&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Abstract&lt;/em>: Research and Education networks play a key role in providing the
data infrastructure to accelerate scientific discovery. This talk will discuss
how the leading Department of Energy user facility in the United States,
ESnet, contributes to scientific discovery and the set of network research
activities including quantum networking currently in progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Biographical Sketch&lt;/em>: Inder Monga provides research and technology
direction, actively leads research projects and manages software engineering
efforts for ESnet. He focuses on advancing networking services for
accelerating collaborative and distributed science, as well as contributes
actively to efforts in the industry related to Software-Defined Networking,
Science DMZ, performance management as well as the Advanced Network
Testbed Initiatives. He is appointed as the chair of ONF&amp;rsquo;s Research
Associates, and contributes actively to the Global Network Architecture
activity. Monga’s research interests include network virtualization, software-
defined networking, grid/cloud computing and sensor networking, and he
holds 17 granted patents. His work experience in the private sector has
included software development, research and network engineering for
Wellfleet Communications and Nortel, where he focused on application and
network convergence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SLICES-PP Receives Funding from the European Commission</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/slices-pp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/slices-pp/</guid><description>&lt;p>Scientific Large Scale Infrastructure for Computing/Communication
Experimental Studies -preparation project (SLICES-PP) is a project with
25 partners and a budget of 3 M€ for 4 years. The UvA will receive 303
K€ and it will be led by Yuri Demchenko of the Informatics Institute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Demchenko, from the CCI (Complex Cyber Infrastructure) group, will
coordinate two topics in SLICES-PP, first Research Data Management in
the SLICES infrastructure, and secondly SLICES capacity building and
career management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a part of activities in SLICES-PP, UvA will also facilitate creating
a SLICES-NL community and involving Dutch research organizations and
universities. The goal is to define the research agenda for SLICES-NL
and coordinate efforts to obtain national funding. In this connection,
new SLICES-NL coordination meetings will be organised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SLICES as a European Research Infrastructure aims to make a fundamental
contribution to research and innovation in digital sciences and
infrastructures, future Internet technologies, future smart networks and
services by providing high quality experimentation services with
emerging technologies around the area of digital sciences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new research infrastructure will allow academics and industry to
experiment and test future, possibly disruptive digital technologies,
essential for European research. This infrastructure can be beneficial
for other scientific and engineering domains, such as smart cities,
energy, green technologies and healthcare.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SLICES-PP will coordinate the preparatory stage to build the future
SLICES Research Infrastructure for Digital Technologies experimentation.
The project was submitted by consortium of 25 research institutions and
centers from 15 countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SLICES-RI (Research Infrastructure) is included in the ESFRI Roadmap
2021 as a new RI for digital technologies experimentation, together with
other already existing RI and e-Infrastructures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://slices-ri.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">More Information&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper accepted at SEAA 2022</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accept-seaa2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accept-seaa2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper &amp;ldquo;UMLsec4Edge: Extending UMLsec to model data-protection-compliant edge computing systems&amp;rdquo; has been accepted as a full paper at the 48th Euromicro Conference on Software Engineering and Advanced Applications (SEAA 2022).
The paper, authored by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> with co-authors from the University of Duisburg-Essen, presents a new UML profile for improved modeling of data protection aspects in edge computing systems.
The practical applicability of the new UML profile is demonstrated with the use cases of the EU-funded research project FogProtect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change of Group Leadership</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</guid><description>&lt;p>As of 1 June 2022, leadership of the Complex Cyber Infrastructure research group was transferred from Prof. Cees de Laat to Dr. Zoltan Mann.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof.dr.ir. Cees de Laat&lt;/a> chaired the System and Network Engineering (SNE) research group since 2006. SNE became so large that on his proposal it was split into three successful research groups in 2020: Complex Cyber Infrastructure (CCI), the Multiscale Networked Systems (MNS), and Parallel Computing Systems (PCS) research groups. Prof. de Laat chaired CCI since the split. His retirement is coming up later this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> is an experienced researcher, who is committed to lead CCI to a further successful future, leveraging his international research and teaching background and industrial leadership experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prof. de Laat and dr. Mann will continue to closely work together to make the transition as smooth as possible.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>