<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/tag/social/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/tag/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Social</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Social</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/tag/social/</link></image><item><title>The Bus Drivers Union wins best outfit prize</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/volleybal-best-outfit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/volleybal-best-outfit/</guid><description>&lt;p>As is tradition, this years volleybal tournament once again contained an SNE team, including
members of CCI and &lt;a href="https://pcs-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PCS&lt;/a>.
To prolong last year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/post/fnwi-volleybal-2023/">achievement&lt;/a>, the team dressed up
as bus drivers, including a pen in their breast pocket and a safety vest to stand out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read more about it on the &lt;a href="https://medewerker.uva.nl/en/science/content-secured/news/2024/06/team-from-iop-wins-volleyball-tournament-2024.html?utm_campaign=240611%20FNWI%20NB%20EN&amp;amp;utm_source=deployteq&amp;amp;utm_medium=e-mail" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Faculty’s staff website&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CCI Demoing at Science Park's Open Day</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/open-day-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/open-day-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>As one of the three representing teams of our Informatics Institute at the Amsterdam
Science Park Open Day, CCI members Kyrian and Marco gave a demo on how scientists
hack hardware&amp;ndash;in an effort to make it more secure, afterwards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was CCI&amp;rsquo;s second participation in the Open Day. It was a great success, with
lots of families amazed by the FPGAs and hardware we showcased and the oscilloscope
showing waveforms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-the-open-day">About the Open Day&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://opendagamsterdamsciencepark.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amsterdam Science Park Open Day&lt;/a>
is a collaboration of Amsterdam Science Park, AMOLF, ARCNL, CWI, Nikhef, and the
University of Amsterdam. It is part of the &lt;a href="https://www.weekendvandewetenschap.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Weekend van de Wetenschap&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
(Weekend of Science), held anually in the first weekend of October. The event is
an initiative of the Dutch Ministry of Education, Culture and Science, aimed to
make the world of science and technology accessible to people of all ages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SNE Volleybal Team Outshines Competition</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/fnwi-volleybal-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/fnwi-volleybal-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Participating at the Faculty of Science&amp;rsquo;s annual volleybal tournament, Team
&lt;em>Snelle Jelle and the Daltons&lt;/em> featuring among others CCI members Tim, Damian,
Christopher and Marco, won the &lt;strong>Most Cheerful Outfit&lt;/strong> prize.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Out of the 16 teams participating, the &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5659248/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>The Daltons&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
look-alikes with fellow members of the MNS and PCS research groups from our SNE
cluster, managed to conquer the 11th place. A very nice result for the first
particpation, which we could not have achieved without our dedicated SNE
supporters that kept cheering for us until the very end. A special thanks to you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Read more about it in the Faculty&amp;rsquo;s staff website
&lt;a href="https://medewerker.uva.nl/en/science/content-secured/news/2023/05/faculty-volleyball-tournament-photanol-sils-wins-again.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Markermeer: the CCI social event</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/social-event-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/social-event-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>To end the academic year in style, the &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Complex Cyber Infrastructure&lt;/a> group went on a sailing trip on the Markermeer.
Before the sailing trip could take off, the group needed to gather in the harbour of Monnickendam &amp;mdash; a beautiful old city with plenty of sightseeing and picture opportunities.
&lt;img src="8P9A9066.JPG" alt="Early birds">&lt;/p>
&lt;p align = "center">
Waiting in the harbour for all members to arrive
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After everyone arrived in the harbour, the captain gave a bit of history on the boat.
The boat was several centuries old, had different owners over time and experienced a couple of world events.
One such event is the second world-war. Since the boat can reach shallow water, it was of upmost interest to the
Germans, because it could be used to supply soldiers on beaches. To prevent usage by the Germans, the boat was
hidden in the Biesbosch during the war.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With some new knowledge on our hands, the sailing trip started. Before sailing with the sails, the boat
went out of the harbour using an engine. This gave todays pirates time to fill their bellies before their labour was needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p float="center" style="display: inline-block;">
&lt;img src="8P9A9073.JPG" width="48%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;img src="8P9A9079.JPG" width="48%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arrived on open water, we could set sail. However, first the sails needed to be hoist.
Several strong members of the group volunteered for this activity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p float="center">
&lt;img src="8P9A9101.JPG" width="48%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;img src="8P9A9128.JPG" width="48%" style="display: inline;" />
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the sails hoisted and a good wind, it was time to relax, socialise and enjoy a couple of drinks.
&lt;img src="8P9A9299.JPG" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p float="center">
&lt;img src="8P9A9223.JPG" width="49%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;img src="8P9A9333.JPG" width="49%" style="display: inline;" />
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a beautiful couple of hours on the water while catching some good winds, it was time
to return to the harbour for a nice barbeque and to welcome &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/ana-oprescu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ana&lt;/a> and her entourage on to the boat.
But first, there were two brave souls, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thomas&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/daphnee-chabal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Daphne&lt;/a>, taking the opportunity to swim.&lt;/p>
&lt;p float="center">
&lt;img src="8P9A9372.JPG" width="49%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;img src="8P9A9363.JPG" width="49%" style="display: inline;"/>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="8P9A9424.JPG" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, it was a great day and being on a sailing boat was a new experience for some. Interesting conversations and discussions were held and new friendships were made.
Are you interested in joining our social event next year? Keep an eye on our news sections for open positions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="acknowledgements">Acknowledgements&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Thanks to &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/yuri-demchenko/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yuri&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/arno-bakker/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Arno&lt;/a>
for taking pictures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ana Oprescu on Travelling as a Mom</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-traveling-as-a-mom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ana-traveling-as-a-mom/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wrote this short piece about travelling with my baby. My point with this, is to bring attention to a compromise parents might not have to make anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Work traveling with Maria.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my home country, mothers can spend up to two years of almost fully paid maternal leave. The Netherlands, with their 16 weeks is a far cry. Luckily, my husband, a freelancing mathematician, can travel with me and take care of Maria while I am participating in the various work activities. As such, Maria has already joined the Nijmegen SusTrainable Teacher Training before she had turned 1, and then joined ICT4S and the SusTrainable summer school. It has not been easy, and the EU does not help in any way, but the UvA is a great employer in this sense, and I can focus much better while traveling for work, knowing I will join Maria in the late afternoon, as if a normal day at ‘home’.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>