<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zoltan Mann | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Zoltan Mann</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>Zoltan Mann</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/</link></image><item><title>IFIP WG11.4 workshop in Ghent</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ifip-11-4-workshop-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ifip-11-4-workshop-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>After a successful recommencement in 2023, &lt;a href="https://www.ifiptc11.org/wg114" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IFIP Working Group 11.4 &amp;ldquo;Network &amp;amp; Distributed Systems Security&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> gathered to a workshop in Ghent on 15-17 May 2024.
Security researchers from several countries discussed cutting-edge research in network and distributed systems security, including the security of distributed machine learning, privacy in distributed systems, and security of the Internet of Things.
CCI was represented by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/daphnee-chabal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Daphnee&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tanjina-islam/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tanjina&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/eloise-zhang/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eloise&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EU project on data protection and self-sovereign identity gets funding</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/licorice-funded/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/licorice-funded/</guid><description>&lt;p>The project &lt;strong>LICORICE (reLIable and sCalable tOols foR self-sovereIgn identity and data proteCtion framEwork)&lt;/strong> is a pan-European cooperation of research and industry players, focusing on developing the next generation of tools and technologies for identity management and data protection.
LICORICE will receive funding of 4 million EUR for 3 years from the European Union, as an innovation action in the Horizon Europe research program.
Within the project, UvA - including CCI researchers &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/kanwal-batool/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kanwal Batool&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> - will mainly focus on privacy-preserving neural network inference.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Large national cybersecurity project gets funding</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/gravitation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/gravitation/</guid><description>&lt;p>The project &lt;strong>Challenges in Cyber Security&lt;/strong> is a cooperation of five Dutch institutions (CWI, RU, TU/e, UvA, and VU) with the aim of making fundamental contributions to security research.
It is one of the seven projects in the Netherlands to receive an &lt;em>NWO Gravitation grant&lt;/em> this year, providing altogether 21.5 million euro funding over the next 10 years.
The UvA team is led by &lt;a href="https://staff.fnwi.uva.nl/c.schaffner/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Christian Schaffner&lt;/a> and includes CCI researchers &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/karst-koymans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Karst Koymans&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/kostas-papagiannopoulos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kostas Papagiannopoulos&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan Mann&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/francesco-regazzoni/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Francesco Regazzoni&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more details, see &lt;a href="https://www.amsec.org/2024/03/nwo-gravitation-21-5-million-euros-for-challenges-in-cyber-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.amsec.org/2024/03/nwo-gravitation-21-5-million-euros-for-challenges-in-cyber-security/&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Best paper award for article in Forensic Science International: Digital Investigation</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/best-paper-aya/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/best-paper-aya/</guid><description>&lt;p>The article &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2666281723000963" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Assessing data remnants in modern smartphones after factory reset&lt;/a>, published in September 2023 in the journal &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/journal/forensic-science-international-digital-investigation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forensic Science International: Digital Investigation&lt;/a>, has won the &lt;strong>Best Paper Award 2023&lt;/strong>.
The paper was selected from a list of high-quality research papers published in FSI:DI over the past two years.
It was judged and praised for its original contribution and high impact in the community.
The paper&amp;rsquo;s authors are: former &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/shared-content/programmas/en/masters/security-and-network-engineering/security-and-network-engineering.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Security and Network Engineering&lt;/a> student Mattheüs B. Blankesteijn, CCI PhD student &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/en/profile/f/u/a.fukami/a.fukami.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Aya Fukami&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/en/profile/g/e/z.j.m.h.geradts/z.j.m.h.geradts.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Professor Zeno Geradts&lt;/a> from the &lt;a href="https://www.forensicinstitute.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Netherlands Forensic Institute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vacancy: Assistant Professor in Future Cloud Computing Technologies</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2024-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2024-02/</guid><description>&lt;p>Join our team!
We have an open Assistant Professor position in the area of Future Cloud Computing Technologies.
Potential research topics include green cloud computing, data management in cloud computing, security and privacy in cloud computing, cloud services for machine learning, sovereignty of cloud services, software engineering for cloud-based software, cloud-to-edge continuum.
See the details and apply here &lt;strong>by 14 April 2024&lt;/strong>:
&lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Assistant-Professor-in-Future-Cloud-Computing-Technologies/788753802/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Assistant-Professor-in-Future-Cloud-Computing-Technologies/788753802/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PhD defense of Xin Zhou</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/defense-xin-zhou/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/defense-xin-zhou/</guid><description>&lt;p>On 16 February 2024, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/xin-zhou/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xin Zhou&lt;/a> successfully defended her PhD dissertation entitled &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>From Empowering to Motivating: Enhancing Policy Enforcement through Process Design and Incentive Implementation&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;. Xin&amp;rsquo;s PhD work was supervised by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cees de Laat&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/tom-van-engers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tom van Engers&lt;/a>, and co-supervised by &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/profiel/b/e/a.s.z.belloum/a.s.z.belloum.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Adam Belloum&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/sander-klous/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sander Klous&lt;/a>. Congratulations to dr. Xin Zhou!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Protection Technologies</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/data_protection_technologies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/data_protection_technologies/</guid><description>&lt;p>The course focuses on technologies that can be used to protect data from unauthorized access. The main motivation is to protect personal data and comply with data protection legislation such as the General Data Protection Regulation of the European Union. The course&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>explains the context of data protection technologies from multiple angles (e.g., legal requirements, interplay with other quality attributes);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>conveys in-depth knowledge on some specific data protection technologies (e.g., cryptographic protocols for secure multi-party computation, anonymization and pseudonymization, differential privacy, access control, anonymous communications);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>showcases applications of data protection technologies (in particular, privacy-preserving machine learning and location privacy).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The course is closely linked to the research performed by CCI researchers in the field of security and privacy (for example, in the &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/project/secured/">SECURED&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/project/fogprotect">FogProtect&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/project/epi">EPI&lt;/a> projects).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lorentz workshop on Future Computing for Digital Infrastructures</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/lorentz-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/lorentz-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.lorentzcenter.nl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lorentz Center&lt;/a> hosted a week-long international workshop on &lt;a href="https://www.lorentzcenter.nl/future-computing-for-digital-infrastructures.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Future Computing for Digital Infrastructures&lt;/a>. More than 40 experts participated and discussed current and future challenges and potential solutions in computing, including the effects on computing by artificial intelligence, sustainability, and security. CCI was represented by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/viktoriya-degeler/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Viktoriya Degeler&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan Mann&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Invited talk at the 2023 Privacy Symposium</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/privacy-symposium-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/privacy-symposium-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> gave an invited talk at this year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://privacysymposium.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Privacy Symposium&lt;/a>, in the session &lt;em>From Cloud to Edge Security&lt;/em>. Entitled &lt;strong>Edge intelligence: friend or foe? (for security and privacy)&lt;/strong>, Zoltan&amp;rsquo;s presentation discussed the security and privacy implications of artificial intelligence in edge computing. It drew attention to the recent BDVA position paper &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/post/bdva-pospaper-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Current Hot Topics in Data Protection&lt;/a> as well CCI&amp;rsquo;s recently started EU research project &lt;a href="https://secured-project.eu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SECURED&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Downloaded Article in Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/wiley-top-downloaded-article-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/wiley-top-downloaded-article-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wiley awarded a &amp;ldquo;Top Downloaded Article&amp;rdquo; certificate to &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> for his paper &lt;a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1002/cpe.6138" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Comparison of workload consolidation algorithms for cloud data centers&lt;/a>, published in the journal &lt;em>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience&lt;/em>. This certifies that the paper was one of the most downloaded during its first 12 months after publication, among work published in 2021. The paper was joint work with Rene Ponto (University of Duisburg-Essen, Germany) and Gabor Kecskemeti (Liverpool John Moores University, UK).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IFIP WG11.4 elects Zoltan Mann as new chair</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/ifip-11-4-chair/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/ifip-11-4-chair/</guid><description>&lt;p>IFIP Working Group 11.4 &amp;ldquo;Network &amp;amp; Distributed Systems Security&amp;rdquo; elected &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> as the new chair of the working group in its meeting on 16 March 2023. Zoltan takes over the chair role from &lt;a href="https://www.uni-regensburg.de/informatik-data-science/wi-kesdogan/team/prof-dr-dogan-kesdogan/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Professor Dogan Kesdogan&lt;/a>, who will continue as secretary of the working group. The new chair and secretary work as acting officers until they are approved by the &lt;a href="https://www.ifiptc11.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IFIP Technical Committee 11&lt;/a> in June 2023.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://ifip.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IFIP&lt;/a>, the International Federation for Information Processing, is the leading multinational, apolitical organization in Information &amp;amp; Communications Technologies and Sciences. It connects researchers worldwide in over 100 Working Groups and 13 Technical Committees.
IFIP Technical Committee 11 is concerned with security and privacy protection in information processing systems, and consists of 14 working groups, addressing different aspects of security and privacy. Working Group 11.4 focuses on security in networks and distributed systems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @PPAI23</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-ppai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-ppai/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>On Achieving Privacy-Preserving State-of-the-Art Edge Intelligence&lt;/b> by Daphnee Chabal, Dolly Sapra,
and Zoltan Mann was accepted at &lt;a
href="https://aaai-ppai23.github.io">&lt;b>4th AAAI Workshop on Privacy-Preserving Artificial Intelligence&lt;/b>&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Deep Neural Networks (DNNs) Inference in Edge Computing, often coined Edge Intelligence, requires solutions to insure that
sensitive data confidentiality and intellectual property are not revealed in the process. Privacy-preserving Edge Intelligence
is only emerging, despite the growing prevalence of Edge Computing as a context of Machine-Learning-as-a-Service. Solutions have
yet to be applied to state-of-the-art DNNs. This position paper provides an original assessment of the compatibility of existing
techniques for privacy-preserving DNN Inference with the characteristics of an Edge Computing setup. The resulting favorite
candidate is secret sharing. We then address the future role of model compression methods in the research towards secret sharing
on DNNs with state-of-the-art performance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Assistant or Associate Professor in Security and Privacy</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2023-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2023-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>Join our team!
We have an open position in the broad area of security and privacy.
The position can be filled on the level of either Assistant Professor or Associate Professor.
See the details and apply here by 15 February 2023:
&lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Assistant-or-Associate-Professor-in-Security-and-Privacy/761330802/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Assistant-or-Associate-Professor-in-Security-and-Privacy/761330802/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two PhD positions on efficient privacy-preserving techniques for data analysis and machine learning</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>How can the privacy of health-related personal data be preserved, while using data analysis and machine learning for innovative medical approaches?
What privacy-preserving techniques should be used and how, to achieve given privacy and utility objectives?
How to implement privacy-preserving techniques to achieve efficiency and scalability?
Work on the answer to these questions as PhD candidate in our research group! See the details and apply here as soon as possible:
&lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Two-PhD-Positions-on-Efficient-Privacy-preserving-Techniques-for-Data-Analysis-and-Machine/760571802/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Two-PhD-Positions-on-Efficient-Privacy-preserving-Techniques-for-Data-Analysis-and-Machine/760571802/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BDVA position paper on data protection</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/bdva-pospaper-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/bdva-pospaper-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Big Data Value Association (BDVA) has just published a new position paper on the latest trends in data protection.
Entitled &amp;ldquo;Current Hot Topics in Data Protection&amp;rdquo; and edited by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan Mann&lt;/a>, the position paper summarizes the latest challenges as well as promising technologies in data protection.
It also presents recommendations for authorities, industry, researchers, and other stakeholders.
You can find more information and download the paper &lt;a href="https://bdva.eu/bdva-publishes-position-paper-latest-trends-data-protection" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open PhD position</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-09/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-09/</guid><description>&lt;p>Is it possible to reduce the energy consumption of machine learning, while increasing its security and privacy? Work on the answer as PhD candidate in our research group! See the details and apply here by 20 September 2022:
&lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/PhD-Position-in-Energy-and-Security-of-Machine-Learning-Applications-in-the-Cloud-to-Edge-Continuum/745019702/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/PhD-Position-in-Energy-and-Security-of-Machine-Learning-Applications-in-the-Cloud-to-Edge-Continuum/745019702/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper accepted at SEAA 2022</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accept-seaa2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accept-seaa2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper &amp;ldquo;UMLsec4Edge: Extending UMLsec to model data-protection-compliant edge computing systems&amp;rdquo; has been accepted as a full paper at the 48th Euromicro Conference on Software Engineering and Advanced Applications (SEAA 2022).
The paper, authored by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> with co-authors from the University of Duisburg-Essen, presents a new UML profile for improved modeling of data protection aspects in edge computing systems.
The practical applicability of the new UML profile is demonstrated with the use cases of the EU-funded research project FogProtect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change of Group Leadership</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</guid><description>&lt;p>As of 1 June 2022, leadership of the Complex Cyber Infrastructure research group was transferred from Prof. Cees de Laat to Dr. Zoltan Mann.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof.dr.ir. Cees de Laat&lt;/a> chaired the System and Network Engineering (SNE) research group since 2006. SNE became so large that on his proposal it was split into three successful research groups in 2020: Complex Cyber Infrastructure (CCI), the Multiscale Networked Systems (MNS), and Parallel Computing Systems (PCS) research groups. Prof. de Laat chaired CCI since the split. His retirement is coming up later this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> is an experienced researcher, who is committed to lead CCI to a further successful future, leveraging his international research and teaching background and industrial leadership experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prof. de Laat and dr. Mann will continue to closely work together to make the transition as smooth as possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cost-optimized, data-protection-aware offloading between an edge data center and the cloud</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-cost-optimized-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-cost-optimized-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Decentralized application placement in fog computing</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-decentralized-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-decentralized-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Security- and Privacy-Aware IoT Application Placement and User Assignment</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-security-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-security-2022/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>