<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zoltan Mann | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Zoltan Mann</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>Zoltan Mann</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/</link></image><item><title>Paper Accepted @PPAI23</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-ppai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-ppai/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>On Achieving Privacy-Preserving State-of-the-Art Edge Intelligence&lt;/b> by Daphnee Chabal, Dolly Sapra,
and Zoltan Mann was accepted at &lt;a
href="https://aaai-ppai23.github.io">&lt;b>4th AAAI Workshop on Privacy-Preserving Artificial Intelligence&lt;/b>&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Deep Neural Networks (DNNs) Inference in Edge Computing, often coined Edge Intelligence, requires solutions to insure that
sensitive data confidentiality and intellectual property are not revealed in the process. Privacy-preserving Edge Intelligence
is only emerging, despite the growing prevalence of Edge Computing as a context of Machine-Learning-as-a-Service. Solutions have
yet to be applied to state-of-the-art DNNs. This position paper provides an original assessment of the compatibility of existing
techniques for privacy-preserving DNN Inference with the characteristics of an Edge Computing setup. The resulting favorite
candidate is secret sharing. We then address the future role of model compression methods in the research towards secret sharing
on DNNs with state-of-the-art performance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Assistant or Associate Professor in Security and Privacy</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2023-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2023-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>Join our team!
We have an open position in the broad area of security and privacy.
The position can be filled on the level of either Assistant Professor or Associate Professor.
See the details and apply here by 15 February 2023:
&lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Assistant-or-Associate-Professor-in-Security-and-Privacy/761330802/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Assistant-or-Associate-Professor-in-Security-and-Privacy/761330802/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two PhD positions on efficient privacy-preserving techniques for data analysis and machine learning</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>How can the privacy of health-related personal data be preserved, while using data analysis and machine learning for innovative medical approaches?
What privacy-preserving techniques should be used and how, to achieve given privacy and utility objectives?
How to implement privacy-preserving techniques to achieve efficiency and scalability?
Work on the answer to these questions as PhD candidate in our research group! See the details and apply here as soon as possible:
&lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Two-PhD-Positions-on-Efficient-Privacy-preserving-Techniques-for-Data-Analysis-and-Machine/760571802/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Two-PhD-Positions-on-Efficient-Privacy-preserving-Techniques-for-Data-Analysis-and-Machine/760571802/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BDVA position paper on data protection</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/bdva-pospaper-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/bdva-pospaper-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Big Data Value Association (BDVA) has just published a new position paper on the latest trends in data protection.
Entitled &amp;ldquo;Current Hot Topics in Data Protection&amp;rdquo; and edited by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan Mann&lt;/a>, the position paper summarizes the latest challenges as well as promising technologies in data protection.
It also presents recommendations for authorities, industry, researchers, and other stakeholders.
You can find more information and download the paper &lt;a href="https://bdva.eu/bdva-publishes-position-paper-latest-trends-data-protection" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open PhD position</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-09/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/vacancy-2022-09/</guid><description>&lt;p>Is it possible to reduce the energy consumption of machine learning, while increasing its security and privacy? Work on the answer as PhD candidate in our research group! See the details and apply here by 20 September 2022:
&lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/PhD-Position-in-Energy-and-Security-of-Machine-Learning-Applications-in-the-Cloud-to-Edge-Continuum/745019702/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/PhD-Position-in-Energy-and-Security-of-Machine-Learning-Applications-in-the-Cloud-to-Edge-Continuum/745019702/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper accepted at SEAA 2022</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accept-seaa2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accept-seaa2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper &amp;ldquo;UMLsec4Edge: Extending UMLsec to model data-protection-compliant edge computing systems&amp;rdquo; has been accepted as a full paper at the 48th Euromicro Conference on Software Engineering and Advanced Applications (SEAA 2022).
The paper, authored by &lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> with co-authors from the University of Duisburg-Essen, presents a new UML profile for improved modeling of data protection aspects in edge computing systems.
The practical applicability of the new UML profile is demonstrated with the use cases of the EU-funded research project FogProtect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change of Group Leadership</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/change-leader/</guid><description>&lt;p>As of 1 June 2022, leadership of the Complex Cyber Infrastructure research group was transferred from Prof. Cees de Laat to Dr. Zoltan Mann.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/cees-de-laat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof.dr.ir. Cees de Laat&lt;/a> chaired the System and Network Engineering (SNE) research group since 2006. SNE became so large that on his proposal it was split into three successful research groups in 2020: Complex Cyber Infrastructure (CCI), the Multiscale Networked Systems (MNS), and Parallel Computing Systems (PCS) research groups. Prof. de Laat chaired CCI since the split. His retirement is coming up later this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cci-research.nl/author/zoltan-mann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Zoltan Mann&lt;/a> is an experienced researcher, who is committed to lead CCI to a further successful future, leveraging his international research and teaching background and industrial leadership experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prof. de Laat and dr. Mann will continue to closely work together to make the transition as smooth as possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cost-optimized, data-protection-aware offloading between an edge data center and the cloud</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-cost-optimized-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-cost-optimized-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Decentralized application placement in fog computing</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-decentralized-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-decentralized-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Security- and Privacy-Aware IoT Application Placement and User Assignment</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-security-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/mann-security-2022/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>