<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>L. Thomas van Binsbergen | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>L. Thomas van Binsbergen</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>L. Thomas van Binsbergen</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/l.-thomas-van-binsbergen/</link></image><item><title>Compiler construction</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/compiler_construction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/compiler_construction/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Programmeertalen</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/programmeertalen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/programmeertalen/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Just happened: Programming Languages in the Netherlands (PLNL) 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/plnl-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/plnl-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>The workshop Programming Languages in the Netherlands, supported by &lt;a href="https://versen.nl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">VERSEN&lt;/a>, was a big success. A 12-presentation programme enticed plenty of discussion amoung the 50-60 participants. The CCI group contributed by organising the event (Thomas and Grace) and by giving two talks (Christopher on Seaso and Damian on language services).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many thanks to Grace for the help in organising the event, resulting in a very smooth workshop experience. The attached pictures give an impression of the event hosted in the Doelenzaal of the university library.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PLNL is still looking for organisers for next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="crowd.jpg" alt="PLNL2023">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inter-faculty UvA funding success for CCI projects</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/rdt-projects-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/rdt-projects-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please find &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/en/content/news/news/2023/05/theme-based-collaboration-enters-next-phase-with-awarding-of-midsize-projects-and-seed-grants.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this&lt;/a> announcement on the internal (UvA) funding awarded for interdisciplinary research within certain themes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thomas, Ana, and Tom with &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/en/about-the-uva/about-the-university/strategy/theme-based-collaboration/responsible-digital-transformations.html#Data-sharing-through-a-data-intermediary" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;Data sharing through a data intermediary&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ana with the project &lt;a href="https://www.uva.nl/en/about-the-uva/about-the-university/strategy/theme-based-collaboration/responsible-digital-transformations.html#Sustainable-privacyenhanced-data" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;Sustainable privacy-enhanced data&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Postdoc Position on Digitally Enforceable Data Sharing contracts</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/sspddp-postdoc-spring2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/sspddp-postdoc-spring2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>The University of Amsterdam (UvA) is looking for a Postdoctoral Researcher in the area of programming languages, formal methods, and distributed systems. The goal of the research is to enable the integration and automatic enforcement of high-level contract specification within distributed systems for data exchange and federated data processing. Possible outcomes are: (domain-specific) software languages, system architecture designs, and prototypes for verifying contract specifications, language implementations, and auditing/monitoring components. The offered contract is for a minimum of 12 months. The closing date is the 25th of June. The ideal starting date the 1st of August.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The full vacancy text and application procedure can be found here: &lt;a href="https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Postdoc-Position-on-Digitally-Enforceable-Data-Sharing-Contracts/771937302/">https://vacatures.uva.nl/UvA/job/Postdoc-Position-on-Digitally-Enforceable-Data-Sharing-Contracts/771937302/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @IEEE eScience 2022</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-escience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-escience/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>Exploring the Enforcement of Private, Dynamic Policies on Medical Workflow Execution&lt;/b> by Christopher A.
Esterhuyse, Tim Muller, Thomas van Binsbergen, and Adam S. Z. Belloum was accepted at &lt;a
href="https://www.escience-conference.org/2022/">18th IEEE eScience Conference 2022: Democratizing Science&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We report on the ideas and experiences of adapting Brane, a workflow execution framework, for use cases involving medical
data exchange and processing. These use cases impose new requirements on the system to enforce policies encoding safety
properties, ranging from access control to legal regulations pertaining to data privacy. Our approach emphasizes users' control
over the extent to which they cooperate in distributed execution, at the cost of revealing information about their policies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @AICOL-JURIX 2022</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-aicol/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-aicol/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>Regulatory Services to Automate Compliance with Ex-post Enforcement&lt;/b> by Lu-Chi Liu, Mostafa Mohajeri Parizi, Thomas van Binsbergen, and Tom van Engers was accepted at &lt;a href="http://www.aicol.eu/">AICOL 2022: AI Approaches to the Complexity of Legal Systems&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Software systems are expected to comply with norms from a variety of sources. However, the increasing volume and the dynamism of norms make it rather difficult to have a fully compliant software system by design. This paper proposes a generic architecture of regulated software systems that facilitates compliance with high-level policies through regulatory services. Our architectural model has the flexibility to adapt to norm modifications and to norm violations by including ex-post enforcement mechanisms. The proposed solution is assessed using a case study and a prototype implementation in the eFLINT and ASC2 languages for modeling norms and software/social agents respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Another Paper Accepted @SLE22</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/second-paper-accepted-at-sle22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/second-paper-accepted-at-sle22/</guid><description>&lt;p>The CCI group is well presented at the &lt;a href="https://2022.splashcon.org/home/sle-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15th edition of the Software Language Engineering (SLE)&lt;/a> with
another paper being accepted, titled: &lt;strong>A Language-Parametric Approach to Exploratory Programming Environments&lt;/strong>
by Thomas van Binsbergen, Damian Frolich, Mauricio Verano Merino, Joey Lai, Pierre Jeanjean, Tijs van der Storm, Benoit Combemale, and Olivier Barais.
This paper is a collaboration with the &lt;a href="https://www.diverse-team.fr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DiverSE team from Inria&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://www.cwi.nl/research/groups/software-analysis-and-transformation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CWI SWAT group&lt;/a>, and a significant contribution from a &lt;a href="https://scripties.uba.uva.nl/search?id=record_30195" target="_blank" rel="noopener">master&amp;rsquo;s thesis&lt;/a> done at the CCI group.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Exploratory programming is a software development style in which code is a medium for prototyping ideas and solutions, and in which even the end-goal can evolve over time. Exploratory programming is valuable in various contexts such as programming education, data science, and end-user programming. However, there is a lack of appropriate tooling and language design principles to support exploratory programming. This paper presents a host language- and object language-independent protocol for exploratory programming akin to the Language Server Protocol. The protocol serves as a basis to develop novel (or extend existing) programming environments for exploratory programming such as computational notebooks and command-line REPLs. An architecture is presented on top of which prototype environments can be developed with relative ease, because existing (language) components can be reused. Our prototypes demonstrate that the proposed protocol is sufficiently expressive to support exploratory programming scenarios as encountered in literature within the software engineering, human-computer interaction and data science domains.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @SLE22</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-at-sle22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-at-sle22/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;strong>iCoLa: A Compositional Meta-language with Support for Incremental Language Development&lt;/strong>
by Damian Frolich and Thomas van Binsbergen is accepted at the &lt;a href="https://2022.splashcon.org/home/sle-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15th edition of the Software Language Engineering (SLE)&lt;/a> conference.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Programming languages providing high-level abstractions can increase programming productivity and safety. Language-oriented programming is a paradigm in which specialized languages are developed to solve problems within specific domains with (high-level) abstractions relevant to those domains. However, language development involves complex design and engineering processes. These processes can be simplified by reusing (parts of) existing languages and by offering language-parametric tooling. In this paper we present iCoLa, a meta-language supporting incremental (meta-)programming based on reusable components. In our implementation of iCoLa, languages are first-class citizens, providing the full power of the host-language (Haskell) to compose and manipulate languages. Finally, we demonstrate iCoLa through a case-study in which we construct &lt;em>Imp&lt;/em>, &lt;em>SIMPLE&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>MiniJava&lt;/em> through the composition and restriction of language fragments and demonstrate the variability of our approach through the construction of several languages using a fixed-set of operators.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Accepted @EUMAS2022</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-eumas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-eumas/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>Introducing Normative Advisors into MAS&lt;/b> by Mostafa Mohajeri Parizi, Thomas van Binsbergen, Giovanni Sileno and Tom van Engers was accepted at &lt;a href="http://www.ccc.cs.uni-duesseldorf.de/eumas2022/">The 19th European Conference on Multi-Agent Systems&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This paper introduces a modular architecture for integrating norms in autonomous agents and multi-agent systems. As the the interactions between norms and agents can be complex, this architecture utilizes multiple programmable components to model concepts such as adoption of multiple personal and/or collective possibly conflicting norms, interpretation and qualification between social and normative contexts, possibility of intentionally (non-)compliant behaviors and resolving conflicts between norms and desires (or other norms). The architecture revolves around &lt;i>normative advisors&lt;/i> that act as the bridge between intentional agents and the institutional reality. As a technical contribution, a running implementation of the architecture is presented based on the ASC2 (AgentScript) BDI framework and eFLINT norm reasoner.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dynamic generation of access control policies from social policies</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-dynamic-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-dynamic-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Generic Back-End for Exploratory Programming</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/frolich-generic-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/frolich-generic-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A principled approach to REPL interpreters</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-principled-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-principled-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>eFLINT: a domain-specific language for executable norm specifications</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-eflint-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/van-binsbergen-eflint-2020/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>