<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>College of Informatics | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/tag/college-of-informatics/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/tag/college-of-informatics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>College of Informatics</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>College of Informatics</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/tag/college-of-informatics/</link></image><item><title>Project Software Engineering</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/project_software_engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/project_software_engineering/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Afstudeerproject BSc Informatiekunde</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/grad_project_bsc_ik/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/grad_project_bsc_ik/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this course Bachelor Information Science students setup and execute a research project exploring an Information Science related research topic under guidance of a researcher. The project results in a bachelor thesis, published in the UvA thesis database. The thesis project runs in period 2/3 as well as in period 5/6.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Afstudeerproject BSc Kunstmatige Intelligentie</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/grad_project_bsc_ki/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/grad_project_bsc_ki/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this course Bachelor Artificial Intelligence students setup and execute a research project exploring an AI-related research topic under guidance of a researcher. The project results in a bachelor thesis, published in the UvA thesis database.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modelleren en Ontwerpen</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/modelleren_en_ontwerpen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/modelleren_en_ontwerpen/</guid><description>&lt;p>The course Modelling and Design is focused on learning domain modelling, and how to create formalised representation. Whilst applying modelling techniques, a broader architectural view is taken, in which students are made aware of choices in e.g. framing and scoping. This course prepares students to exchange knowledge with domain stakeholders, and to communicate potential design decisions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Operating Systems</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/operating_systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/operating_systems/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the Operating Systems course, students learn how applications
interact with the hardware via the operating system, and how the
operating system solves various tasks for the applications such as CPU
scheduling, and memory and storage management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Understanding these basics is very important to analyse and tune the
performance of a system to a particular application. In the Complex
Cyber Infrastructure group, we are often dealing with very high
performance hardware, such as 400 Gbps fiber links, and large storage
volumes. To have e.g. data-processing applications make full use of this
hardware, requires tuning the operating system to the specific workload,
and this is where the fundamental operating system knowledge comes in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compiler construction</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/compiler_construction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/compiler_construction/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Organisatie: analyse en ontwikkeling</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/organisatie_analyse_en_ontwikkeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/organisatie_analyse_en_ontwikkeling/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the course Organisational Analysis and Developement (in Dutch Organisatieontwikkeling and -ontwikkeling) we study how collaborations between organisations influence IT-architectures that support cross-organisational collaboration. Particularly, we focus on data-sharing aspects and usage control that is required to create trust essential to collaboration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programmeertalen</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/programmeertalen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/programmeertalen/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Web and Media Tech</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/web_and_media_tech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/web_and_media_tech/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Computer Systems</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/computer_systems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/computer_systems/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introduction to Security</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/introduction_to_security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/introduction_to_security/</guid><description>&lt;p>Security is one of the most important extra-functional property of systems. Essential yet often overlooked, security ensures that our daily transactions remain protected, that our infrastructure operates regularly and that our communication stays private and safe from unauthorized parties. The aim of Introduction to Security is to provide solid foundations on the overall security domain, starting from the core components of cryptographic theory, implementations and cryptanalysis. Subsequently, it shows how secure are used to build the cryptographic protocols deployed in our everyday life, and we continue by covering the fundamentals of operating systems&amp;rsquo; security, intrusion detection/prevention and recent research topics such as privacy-preserving technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within CCI, our research strives to develop and apply open-source, efficient, protected and tailor-made cryptographic implementations that ensure the security, privacy and availability of our society&amp;rsquo;s communication infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Netwerkorganisatie</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/netwerkorganisatie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/teaching/netwerkorganisatie/</guid><description>&lt;p>The course Network Organisation is focused on the questions why and how organisations collaborate in a complex environment. Studying those collaborations students are aimed to get better insights in how organisations function in a dynamic context. The students use system dynamic modelling to represent those collaborations and develop quantitative dynamic models that support policy decisions that affect the stakeholders in such complex enviroment&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>