<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Xin Zhou | Complex Cyber-Infrastructures (CCI)</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/xin-zhou/</link><atom:link href="https://cci-research.nl/author/xin-zhou/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Xin Zhou</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://cci-research.nl/images/logo_hu5a1000236f6e181a977795e6532452c2_304385_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url><title>Xin Zhou</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/author/xin-zhou/</link></image><item><title>Paper Accepted @IEEE TPS 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-tps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-accepted-tps/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>Enabling Collaborative Multi-Domain Applications: A Blockchain-Based Solution with Petri Net Workflow Modeling and Incentivization&lt;/b> by Zhou, X., Cushing, R., Koning, R., Belloum, A., Grosso, P., Klous, S., van Engers, T. &amp; de Laat, C. was accepted at &lt;a
http://www.sis.pitt.edu/lersais/conference/tps/2023/">The Fifth IEEE International Conference on Trust, Privacy and Security in Intelligent Systems, and Applications&lt;/a>. &lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The increasing value of data and the emergence of programmable infrastructures have paved the way for collaborative multi-domain applications across industries such as healthcare and airlines. However, such collaborations come with significant challenges, including application coordination, incentivization, and validation of execution. In this paper, we propose a novel solution that leverages blockchain technology and utilizes Petri nets for workflow modeling. Our approach involves implementing a smart contract-based workflow coordinator on the blockchain and employing a three-layered architecture to coordinate off-chain tasks. Additionally, we demonstrate the use of Petri nets for modeling economy tokens, which serve as incentives to foster collaboration among workflow parties. To validate our solution, we present a proof of concept through a simulated use case involving a multi-domain workflow for mitigating a DDoS attack. In this use case, domains collaborate by blocking offending IPs, incentivized by acquired tokens required to invoke workflows.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Paper Published@AMC 2023</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-published-amc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/post/paper-published-amc/</guid><description>&lt;p>The paper titled &lt;b>The dynamics of corruption under an optional external supervision service&lt;/b> by Xin Zhou, Adam Belloum, Michael H. Lees, Tom van Engers, Cees de Laat has been published at &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0096300323003417">Applied Mathematics and Computation&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Abstract:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>External supervision services play an important role in combating corruption by detecting potential collusive bribery. This work aims at studying the dynamics of collusive bribery when participants have the option of engaging the external supervision services. To do so, we construct a basic model where collusive bribery can happen between the defecting participants who aim to escape from a punishment by offering a bribe to rule enforcers who monitor interactions among all participants. Among rule enforcers, only the corrupt ones accept the bribe and ignore the violations. The cooperative participants can engage the external supervision service at a certain cost to avoid the risk of potential collusive bribery. Under the framework of evolutionary game theory, we find that a higher initial fraction of honest enforcers is more likely to lead to a trusting cooperating equilibrium. We also find that, when allowing random exploration of available strategies, increasing the exploration rate of rule enforcers is effective in combating corruption for both infinite and finite populations. Lastly, we find that minimizing the cost of external supervision services is not always good. When the system evolves into a cooperating equilibrium, a low cost of external supervision service induces unnecessary costs of seeking external supervision. When the strategy profiles exhibit stable oscillations, there exists an optimal cost of external supervision, considering the trade-off between minimizing the chance of exposing cooperative participants to collusive bribery and strengthening the punishment on the corrupt enforcers. Premised on the results, we discuss practical management suggestions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Costly incentives design from an institutional perspective: cooperation, sustainability and affluence</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/proceeding_a_xin_2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/proceeding_a_xin_2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Policy Enforcement for Secure and Trustworthy Data Sharing in Multi-domain Infrastructures</title><link>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-policy-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cci-research.nl/publication/zhou-policy-2020/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>